[MUSIC]
(音乐)
Stanford University, >> So
斯坦福大学> >
斯坦福大学
welcome to Stanford CS193P, this is Developing iOS
欢迎来到斯坦福CS193P,这是开发iOS
欢迎参加 2017 年冬季学期斯坦福 CS193P 课程
Applications, winter of 2017, So today I'm gonna give
应用程序,2017年冬天,所以今天我要给
iOS 应用程序开发
another brief set of slides on Model View Controller, this
另一个简单的幻灯片在模型-视图-控制器,这个
今天的幻灯片是关于 MVC，模型——视图——控制器
design methodology that we're gonna use to build all of our
设计方法,我们将使用我们所有的
一个编写所有 iOS 程序都会用到的设计模式
iOS apps, And then I'm gonna continue the demo that we
iOS应用程序,然后继续我们的演示
之后就接着完成星期一开始的
started on Monday, We're gonna actually incorporate MVC into
周一开始,我们会结合MVC
那个程序。我们会把这种设计模式
the calculator, And it's also gonna be an opportunity for
计算器,它也会是一个机会
运用到计算其中。这也是一个大好机会
me to show you a lot of other cool Swift, language features,
我给你很多其他降温迅速、语言特性,
能让我展示 Swift 的许多优点、语法和特性
So what is MVC? Model view controller, what is that?
MVC是什么?
什么是 MVC，模型——视图——控制器呢？
Basically, it starts out being a way that we divide up
基本上,它开始成为我们划分
从大体上看，这是我们把代码
all of the code in our app into three different camps,
所有的代码在我们的应用程序分成三个不同的阵营,
分割成了三个“阵营”
These three different camps are the model camp, the model
这三个不同阵营的阵营的模型,模型
“阵营”的一个是 Model，模型
is the "what" of your app, so what your app is, So,
是你的应用的“什么”,所以你的应用是什么,所以,
模型体现了你的程序“是什么”，也就是你的程序是干什么的
in the calculator case, it's the brains of the calculator,
计算器,计算器的大脑,
用计算器来举例子，那模型就是它的大脑
it's the thing that calculates, tha's the model,
这是计算的东西,那是模型,
负责计算的那个部分就是模型
and tha's a UI independent part, It's what the app is,
和那一个UI的独立部分,它的应用是什么,
和 UI 是没有关系的。仅仅是背后的逻辑
not how it displays or anything like that,
不是它如何显示或类似的东西,
和具体怎么展示出来是没有关系的
How it displays is the controlle's job, So
它显示是怎样controlle的工作,所以呢
决定如何展示的是 Controller，控制器
the controller decides how to take this UI independent
控制器独立决定如何把这个UI
控制器决定如何把这个与 UI 无关的
thing, the model, and display it on your screen and
模型,并将其显示在你的屏幕上
这个模型显示到你的屏幕上
interact with the user, That's what the controller job does,
与用户交互,控制器的工作是什么,
来和用户交互。这就是控制器的作用
It's the, how it displays, Model is the what it is,
它是,它显示,模型是什么,
决定如何展示出来。模型是程序的本体
Controller is how it displays,
控制器是如何显示,
控制器决定如何展示
The view is the minions of the controller, okay?
视图控制器的奴才,好吗?
View，视图，是控制器手下的用人
Things that the controller uses to do its job,
控制器用来做它的工作的事情,
控制器通过视图来实现它的功能
almost always, these things in the view are generic,
几乎总是,这些东西在视图中是通用的,
通常视图都是能通用的
things like UIButton or UIScrollView, okay?
UIButton或UIScrollView,好吗?
比如 UIButton 或者 UIScrollView
Things that come from Apple or somewhere else,
来自苹果或其他地方的事情,
由苹果或是其它平台提供的
even things you write, and you generally try to write them to
即使是你写,你通常试着写
包括你自己编写的。你应该尽量写通用的
be pretty generic reusable UI things, And the controller is
非常通用的可重用的UI,以及控制器
能够重用的 UI 控件。而控制器
trying to use those generic things to build a specific UI,
试图建立一个特定的UI使用这些通用的东西,
则是使用这些通用的控件构成特有的 UI
Now the key to making MVC work is managing the communication
现在使MVC工作的关键是管理沟通
使用 MVC 的关键是组织联系
between these camps because if we don't manage
这些阵营之间,因为如果我们不管理
这几个阵营。如果我们
that communication,
沟通,
没有控制好交互
we might as well just put them all in the big camp,
我们不妨把它们全部在大营地,
而只是把这些代码都堆在一起
And they can all talk to each other however they want, So
他们都能互相交谈但是他们想要的,所以
三个阵营之间都能随便调用的话
if we're gonna have three camps,
如果我们要有三个阵营,
那这分类也就没什么实际意义了
we gotta think about how they communicate,
我们必须考虑他们如何沟通,
所以我们要考虑好三者之间是如何交互的
So I've used this road sign kind of imagery here, okay,
所以我用这个路标的意象,好吧,
我这里用的道路交通标线来表示
the roads, like the road lines in the middle of a road
的道路,就像路行中间的路
就是马路中间的那些线
between them to help you visualize what is allowed
他们之间帮助你想象什么是允许的
让你们能形象地理解
in terms of communication,
在沟通方面,
哪些沟通是被允许的
So, let's talk about every boundary here between all of
所以,让我们来谈谈每一边界之间的所有
让我们来逐个分析阵营之间的交互
these camps, Let's start with the controller talking to
这些营地,先从控制器
我们从控制器访问模型开始
the model, okay, Can the controller talk to
模型,控制器能跟
控制器能和模型通信吗？
the model? Absolutely, it can say anything to the model that
这个模型吗?
肯定是可以的。控制器能够访问
the model publicly allows to be said to itself, So,
模型公开允许说本身,所以,
模型所有公开允许访问的内容
it's a green arrow, It's a dashed white line on the road,
这是一个绿色的箭头,这是一个白色虚线在路上,
所以我用绿箭头。这是白虚线
You can go across there all you want,
你可以在那里所有你想要的,
你可以随便跨过去
And you can see why this is,
你可以看到为什么这是
这是可以理解的
It is the controller job to get that model onto screen,
控制器的工作得到模型在屏幕上,
因为控制器的功能就是把模型展示到屏幕上
It has to be able to talk to it all at once, So, there's no
它能够跟它一次,所以,没有
控制器应该是有全权处理的
restriction of the controller talking to the model, And
控制器与模型的限制,
控制器访问模型是没有限制的
similarly, there's no restriction of the controller
同样的,没有限制的控制器
同样的，也不会限制控制器
talking to the view, because the view are the controller's
说到视图,因为视图控制器
与视图的沟通，因为视图和控制器
minions, Right, so you gotta be able to tell your minions
奴才,对吧,所以你必须能够告诉你的仆从
是从属关系。你肯定要能够和下属沟通
what to do without restriction, Now,
没有什么限制,现在,
告诉它们该做什么。这不应该被限制
these connections between the controller and
这些控制器和之间的连接
这些控制器和视图之间的关连
a view, we call them outlets, And you've already seen one in
一个视图,我们称之为媒体,你已经看过的
叫做 Outlet，出口。你们已经在计算器里见到过了
the calculator, we created an outlet, if you remember,
计算器,我们创建了一个出口,如果你还记得,
如果你还记得的话，我们创建的那个出口
it was called display, right?
它被称为显示,对吧?
就是叫做 display 的那个
It was an instance variable in our controller, Remember that
这是一个实例变量在我们的控制器,记住这一点
控制器的实例变量
class ViewController we saw on Monday,
类ViewController周一我们看到,
星期一看到的那个 ViewController 类
that's the controller of the MVC that we built on Monday,
MVC的控制器,我们建立了周一,
我们周一就是构建了那个控制器
And that display var, was an outlet,
显示变量,是一个出口,
那个变量 display 就是 outlet 出口
and it's just wired up to a UILabel in our view, UILabel
这是连接到UILabel在我们看来,UILabel
和视图里面的 UILabel 关连起来的
is one of the minions for the controller in the view, Okay,
是一个奴才的控制器在视图中,好吧,
那个 UILabel 就是视图中、控制器下属的其中一个
so you've already seen that happen, The model and the view
所以你已经看到这种情况发生,模型和视图
所以你们已经见过这种交互了。模型和视图
can never speak to each other, Double orange line there,
不能说话,双橙线,
它们之间是不能有交互的。双黄线
no crossing either way across here, And this makes perfect
没有交叉穿过,这使得完美
两边都不能跨线。这也是很有道理的
sense because the model is completely UI independent,
因为模型是完全独立于UI,
因为模型是完全和 UI 分开的
and the view is completely UI, That's all the view is,
和观点是完全的UI,所有的观点是,
而视图全部是 UI 相关的
So, they have nothing to talk about,
所以,他们没有谈论,
所以它们并没有共同语言
these two guys, okay? Cuz they're completely, you know,
这两个家伙,好吗?
这两者之间，你知道的
different camps that make no sense to talk to each other,
不同的阵营,相互交谈没有任何意义,
它们的交互完全是天方夜谭
It's up to the controller to manage communication between
由控制器来管理之间的通信
控制器才是负责它们之间交互的
these two, So, never shall you just communicate between those
这两个,所以,从不将之间的沟通
所以永远不要让模型和视图互相调用
two camps, all right? How about the view talking back to
两个阵营?
好吧？那视图反过来，和控制器交互呢？
its controller? Can the view, those minions, can they talk
它的控制器?
视图，作为仆从，能够联系
to its controller? Now this is something you would clearly
其控制器吗?
它的控制器吗？很明显的，这是我们希望有的
want because the minions gotta work with the controller, but
希望因为奴才要处理控制器,但是
因为它们是给控制器干活的
it's a bit of a problem here,
这是一个问题,
但存在一个小问题
Because these things in the view are generic,
因为这些东西在视图中是通用的,
那就是这些控件都是通用的
They're things like UIButton, The class UIButton shipped
他们像UIButton,类UIButton装船
就像 UIButton 那样的
from Apple last year, It knows nothing about a calculator,
从去年的苹果,它一个计算器,一无所知
苹果去年编写的 UIButton 类对我们计算器一无所知
so how can that UIButton talk to a calculator? Well, we can
所以如何UIButton跟计算器吗?
那么 UIButton 要怎么和我们计算器通信呢？
do it, We just have to sort of do it in a blind, meaning
这样做,我们只需要用一个盲人,意思吗
可是可以，不过它是被蒙在鼓里的
we don't know the class of the thing we're talking to,
我们不知道的事情我们说的类,
因为我们并不知道我们联系的究竟是谁
And structured manner, so that we can clearly understand what
和结构化的方式,这样我们就可以清楚地理解
这个通信也是规范化的，才能保证大家都能理解
communication is happening, So you've already seen a blind
通信正在发生,所以你已经看到一个盲人
发送的是什么信息。你已经看到过这样的
structured communication between the view and
结构化视图和之间的沟通
规范化的匿名通讯，在视图
the controller, It's target action, okay, So
控制器,它的目标行动,所以
和控制器之间使用。这叫 target-action，目标对象-操作模式
the controller can drop a target on itself
控制器可以降低目标
控制器可以把自己设置为目标
by basically creating a method with that @IBAction,
通过与这@IBAction基本上创建一个方法,
然后创建个响应对应 @IBAction 操作的方法
remember that from Monday? And then you just control drag and
还记得从周一吗?
还记得我们星期一的时候干的吗？按住 Control 键拖拽
that lets the view UIButton talk,
让视图UIButton说话,
来创建 UIButton 视图的通讯
basically connect up to that target, And now every
基本上连接这一目标,现在每一个
也就是关连那个通讯目标
time that the UIButton wants to talk to the controller,
次UIButton想跟控制器,
现在每次那个 UIButton 想要给控制器发送消息
it's just sending that target action, So that is
只是发送目标动作,这就是
只需要把操作发送给目标对象即可
super simple blind structured communication from the view
超级简单盲目的结构化的沟通从视图
这就是视图使用的标准化匿名通讯机制
back to the controller, But, that's a little too simple for
控制器,但这有点太简单了
并以此来联系控制器。但是有的时候
all the communication that these minions might wanna do,
所有这些奴才的沟通可能要做,
这种方式不足以实现这些下属的需求
For example, sometimes, something in the view wants to
例如,有时候,在视图中想要的东西
比如有时候视图想要
synchronize itself with the controller,
同步控制器本身,
和控制器保持同步
Or it wants to know what the controller intends as it's
也想知道控制器的计划
或了解控制器使用自己想达到的目标
being used, Let's use the example of a scroll view,
正在使用,让我们使用滚动视图的例子,
拿 UIScrollView 举例子
Okay, a scroll view,
好的,滚动视图,
滚动视图
when it's scrolling around,
滚动的时候,
在四处滑动的时候
might wanna ask the controller,
可能想问控制器,
可能会想问控制器
should I allow the user to scroll over here? Or
我应该允许用户滚动呢?
我能让用户滑动到这里吗？
they might just wanna tell the controller, hey, the user
他们可能只是想告诉控制器,嘿,用户
或者想要告诉控制器
scrolled down here, These kind of notifications and
和滚动,这样的通知
用户已经滑动到这里了。这种通知
questions about whether it can do things, they kind of end up
问题是否能做事情,他们最终
和询问能否做某些事情的行为
in things that start with these words I have up here,
的东西从上面这些话我已经开始,
通常都能被这样归类
"will," "should," and "did," Like,
“将”、“应该”和“,”,
“will”（将要），“should”（能否）和“did”（已经）
should I scroll to here? I will scroll right here,
我要滚动到这里吗?
“我应该滑动到这里吗”？“我将要滑动到这里”
if the scroll view was about to scroll, And
如果滚动视图滚动,
如果滚动视图要开始滑动了
then I did scroll down here after the scroll view is done,
我往下滚动视图完成后,
以及完成之后的“我已经滑动到这里了”
So those kinds of communications,
这些类型的通信,
就是这类的通讯
And the way we make that communication work,
和我们进行沟通的方式工作,
我们实现这类沟通的方法
we can't just do this simple one method control drag,
我们不能只做这简单的一个方法控制阻力,
并不只是简单的按 Control 拖拽
instead we use what's called a delegate, And I'm gonna talk
相反,我们使用所谓的代表,我要说话
而是通过 delegate，委托代理
a lot more about a delegate in future lectures, But basically
更多关于一个委托在以后的讲座,但基本上
之后的课程里我会细讲委托模式
the idea of a delegate is, it's a var in the view, so
一个委托的想法是,这是一个var在视图中,
简单来说代理是视图里的一个变量
like a var on scroll view, And it's of a special type; that
像一个var滚动视图,这是一种特殊类型,
比如 UIScrollView 里的一个属性，类型十分特殊
type is called a protocol, I know that a lot of you,
类型被称为一个协议,我知道你们很多人,
叫做 protocol，协议。我知道你们大部分人
even though you have object oriented experience,
即使你有面向对象的经验,
即使有使用面向对象编程的经验
maybe you don't have experience with protocols, But
也许你没有经验的协议,但是
也很有可能没有使用过协议
essentially, a protocol is a way of
从本质上讲,一个协议的一种方式
协议本质上是一种
saying that this type, this thing that I'm talking about,
说这个类型,这个东西,我说的是,
我这里的这个变量
it responds to a certain set of methods, I don't know what
这对一个特定的方法,我不知道
能够响应这些方法
class it is, I don't know if it's a view controller,
类,我不知道这是一个视图控制器,
我不知道它具体是什么类型，也不知道是不是 ViewController
I don't know what it is, but
我不知道那是什么,但是
虽然我不知道具体是什么
I know it's gonna respond to these methods like will
我知道它会回应这些方法等
但是我知道它拥有这些方法，比如
scroll, did scroll, should scroll,
滚动,滚动,滚动,
willScroll, didScroll, shouldScroll
those kinds of methods, That's all I know about it, So
这些方法,这就是我知道的,所以
我所知道的就是它有这类的方法
the controller, it signs up to listen to those methods,
控制器,它报名听这些方法,
所以控制器如果想要监听这些事件
and then it sets itself as the delegate in the view,
然后它集本身为委托在视图中,
就可以把自己设为视图的 delegate
Okay, and we're gonna see this in action, so
好的,我们会看到在行动,
我们还会实际用到的
don't worry about too much now, but that's how we can
现在不要担心太多,但我们可以
所以现在理解不了不用担心
have structured communication where they're agreeing,
结构化的沟通,他们同意,
不过这就是规范通讯的方法
The view, this generic object is agreeing to
看来,这个通用的对象是同意
通用的视图同意
send certain messages to the controller,
某些消息发送到控制器,
给控制器发送一定的信息
not where the controller can be of any type and
并不是任何类型的控制器可以
所以控制器可以是任何类型的
still serve this purpose of controlling its view,
仍然服务于这一目的的控制它的视图,
同时又能实现控制视图的功能
Now there's a special kind of communication between the view
现在有一种特殊的视图之间的沟通
控制器和视图之间还有一种特殊的联系
and the controller that arises because a view cannot own
视图和控制器,是因为不能自己
起因是视图不会包含它所需要的数据
the data it displays, And what does that mean? That means you
数据显示,这是什么意思?
这是什么意思呢？
don't want to have inside your view class, and remember, view
不想在你的视图类,记住,视图
这意味着你不希望在视图
classes are like scroll views, buttons, things like that,
类就像滚动视图、按钮,
也就是比如滚动视图，按钮这些类中
You don't wanna have data in there that is
你不想有数据
你不希望有特定的数据
the data you're displaying, I'll give you an example,
你显示的数据,我将给你一个例子,
也就是要展示的数据。我们举个例子
Let's say your entire iPod music library,
假设你的整个iPod音乐库,
比如你 iPod 里面的音乐库
let's say you have hundreds of thousands of songs in there,
假设你有成千上万的歌曲,
里面有成千上万的歌曲
Okay, so I wanna have a list of them on screen, So
好的,所以我想有一个列表在屏幕上,所以
我希望把它们展示出来
I'm gonna use a generic item in my view called table view,
我将使用一个通用的项目在我看来称为表视图,
因此我用一个通用的 UITableView 来展示
Table view just shows a big long list of something,
表视图只显示一大长串的东西,
表格视图的功能是显示一长串内容
It can be a list a million items long, okay? So
它可以是一个一百万个条目的列表,好吗?
比如一个有一百万项内容的列表
if I really had to take my entire iPod library and
如果我真的要把我整个图书馆和iPod
如果我需要把整个音乐库里的歌曲
put it in the value of a var of
把它放在的var的价值
放到 UITableView 的某个变量中
the table view to display it, that would be ridiculous,
表视图显示它,那将是荒谬的,
让它去展示，那这样做是很荒唐的
Not just from a performance standpoint, but
不仅从性能的角度来看,但是
先不考虑程序的性能
now I have two copies of my iPad, or
现在我有两个我的iPad的副本,或
因为我现在相当于有两个 iPad
my iPod music library, one inside this table view, and
我的iPod音乐库,一个在这个表格视图,
有两个 iPad 的音乐库：一个在表格视图里
one in some database somewhere in my phone, That's bad, where
一个在某些数据库在我的电话,那就糟糕了,
一个在 iPhone 上的某个数据库里。这是不合适的
they could get out of sync, managing the synchronicity,
他们可能会不同步,管理同步,
它们无法保持同步，内容可能会过时
what if I have multiple apps doing that? Ugh,
那如果我有多个应用程序做什么?
又比如我有很多个程序都在这么做呢？
it's a mess, so the view never wants to own that data, okay?
这是一片混乱,所以从来没有想自己的数据视图,好吗?
那简直是一团糟。所以视图不应该保存一份数据
So how the heck is it gonna get the data then?
所以到底是如何得到的数据呢?
那又要从哪里获得数据呢？
I've got 100,000 songs, I need to show it in this table,
我有100000首歌曲,我需要显示这个表,
我这里有很多首歌，我需要把它们显示到列表里
how's it gonna do it? Well, it's gonna use another one of
它会怎么做?
实现的方法是通过另一个
these protocol based vars, okay, called the data source,
这些协议基于var,所谓的数据源,
存储协议类型的变量，这个叫做 dataSource
And the data source has different methods in it,
数据源有不同的方法,
数据源拥有和代理不一样的方法
it's not will, should, did, it's how many items are in
这不是应该会做的,有多少物品
就不是 will，should 和 did 了。数据源知道有多少
this piece of data? Give me the data at this location, And
这段数据?
也就是数据的具体个数，这个位置的数据是什么
that, again, is a var that controllers
再次,这是一个控制器的var
控制器会把 dataSource
set in the table view, let's say, that points back to it,
设置在表视图中,比方说,点回来,
表格视图里的变量设为自己
And so now every time the table view wants data,
现在每次表视图要数据,
之后表格视图想要数据的时候
it asks the controller, And the controller almost
它要求控制器,控制器几乎
就会问 dataSource，也就是控制器
always turns around and asks the model, give me that data,
总是在问模型,给我这些数据,
接着控制器一般会问模型，让它提供数据
Now this also allows something like table view that's showing
这还允许类似的表视图显示
所以对于那些需要显示大量数据的表单视图
100,000 items, It can only show 10 on a screen at a time,
100000件,它只能显示10在屏幕上,
因为实际屏幕上每次只能显示 10 个
so it only asks for 10 and shows them, And if you scroll
所以它只要求10,显示了他们,如果你滚动
可以只临时获得 10 条数据来显示。如果你向下滑
down to somewhere else, it's gonna ask for that 10,
到别的地方,它会要求10,
滑动到了其它地方，它又去要另外 10 条
And it's only keeping the ones it's displaying, So
只有保持的显示,所以
每次只缓存当前展示部分的数据
it's transferring a lot less data, only the data you're
将少了很多数据,只有你的数据
所以每次传送的数据都很少，只是实际上
actually viewing, 10 out of 100,000 songs, And so it's
实际上看,10的100000首歌曲,这是
在展示的部分，比如十万首歌只选十首
a lot more efficient, both in terms of memory usage and
更高效,无论是内存使用
因此也变得更加高效，包括使用更少的内存
everything, Now you might be a little scared,
一切,现在你可能会有点害怕,
和其它的方面。现在你可能会担心
like, every single time I'm gonna scroll,
每一次我要滚动,
每次我滑动的时候
I'm gonna be asking for
我要要求
我都要去获取这些数据啊
this data, But keep in mind, the model for
这些数据,但记住,模型
这你不必担心，你想想
the iPod's music library is probably a SQL database or
iPod的音乐库可能是一个SQL数据库或
iPod 音乐库很有可能是类似于 SQL 的数据库
something, something that can serve up data super fast,
东西,可以提供数据非常快,
能够快速地获得数据
That's it's job as a model to be the source of that data,
它的工作模式是数据的来源,
这是它作为模型的任务就是提供数据
okay? So that is usually not your performance bottleneck,
好吧?
所以一般不会在性能上拖你的后腿
We're gonna talk about performance later in this
我们将讨论性能在稍后
之后的课程我们会讲到性能
class, by the way, Usually the performance bottleneck is
类,顺便说一下,通常性能瓶颈
这方面你通常会遇到的瓶颈
drawing on the screen, Things like getting data out of
在屏幕上绘图,得到数据
是在屏幕上绘制内容。像这种从数据库中获取数据
databases, forget it, Drawing on the screen is much slower
数据库,忘记它,画在屏幕上是慢得多
你可以忽略不计。在屏幕上绘制很慢
and then going over the network is even slower,
然后通过网络更慢,
通过网络加载内容更慢
So those things tend to dominate the performance of
所以这些东西往往主宰的性能
这些才是影响你程序性能的主要原因
your app, Okay, so don't worry about that, So anyway, so
你的应用,所以不要担心,总之,
所以可以放心大胆地从模型加载数据
that's a couple of examples how we have the structured
这是几个例子如何结构化
通过这几个例子，我们具体了解了
communication from generic objects back to our
回到我们的沟通从通用的对象
通用控件是如何采用规范化的通讯模式
controller, Now what about sorry, one statement that's
控制器,那么对不起,一个声明
联系控制器的。等等，还有一句话
good to put in your mind that has all three camps in it,
好把你脑海中有三个阵营,
你最好记住，在这三个阵营中
is that the controller interprets and formats
这是控制器解释和格式吗
控制器负责把模型里的数据
the model for its views, Cuz its views are generic, they
模型的观点,因为其观点是通用的,他们
转化为视图能接受的类型。因为视图是通用的
don't really know how to deal with any particular model,
真的不知道如何处理任何特定的模型,
它们并不知道如何处理任何特定的模型
A controller knows about both, so that's part of its job,
一个控制器知道,这是其工作的一部分,
但控制器知道，所以由它负责
So a lot of times I'll be saying,
很多时候我会说,
以后我会常说
the controller's job is to do this, and you'll be like,
控制器的工作是要做到这一点,你会喜欢,
“控制器负责这个”。这时候
yeah, I remember him saying that, All right, now what
是的,我记得他说,好吧,现在
你最好能想起我提到过这个。好，下一个
about the model communicating with the controller?
模型与控制器通信呢?
模型去联系控制器呢？
Now this can never happen as well because the model is
这也永远不会发生,因为模型
这是不应该发生的，就像模型不依赖 UI 一样
UI independent, It knows nothing about any particular
UI独立,它任何特定一无所知
模型对用户界面一无所知
UI, so there's no way it could talk to a UI guy like
UI,所以没有办法和一个UI的家伙说话
所以它不能够和负责 UI 的控制器交流
the controller, okay? So what happens, though, if the model
控制器,好吗?
那如果模型发生了变化呢？
changes, the data changes? That controller needs to know,
变化,数据变化?
数据发生了改变呢？控制器必须要知道啊
because it wants to update the screen in that case,
因为它想更新屏幕在这种情况下,
这样它才能更新显示的数据
Well, the way we do that is with a model that
我们做的模型
我们实现的方法是
kind of looks like a radio station, okay? The model
看起来像一个电台,好吗?
在模型中建立一个“电台”
basically has a radio station, and it broadcasts on that
主要有一个广播电台,广播
通过这个电台发送广播通知
radio station, hey, I changed, or this about me changed, And
广播电台,嘿,我改变了,或者对我改变,
说“数据发生变化了”，或者是“这部分数据发生了变化”
then the controller tunes in to that radio station, And
然后控制器音乐电台,和
控制器通过观察收听的那个电台
when it hears a broadcast, it asks the model what changed,
当它听到广播,它问模型改变,
在接到通知的时候，就问模型什么数据变了
down that green arrow there, you see? Okay, so
绿色箭头,你看到了吗?
还是通过我们这里的这个绿色通道
that's the model we're gonna use, that's the mechanism
我们将使用的模型,这是机制
所以这就是我们用的机制
we're gonna use to get stuff for our model that changes
我们会使用更改为我们的模型得到的东西
通过这种方式让模型
to notify our controller, Some people ask, can
通知我们的控制器,有些人问,可以
通知控制器。有人会问
a view tune in to a radio station? And the answer is,
一个视图收听电台?
视图应该收听那个电台吗？当然你可以
yeah, it probably could, It wouldn't necessarily violate
是的,它可能不一定会违反
也并不一定会违背 MVC 的原则
MVC, But the problem is a generic view wouldn't know
MVC,但问题是不知道通用视图
但问题是，通用的视图并不知道
what radio station to tune into anyway, so it's really
什么电台收听,这是真的
具体要收听哪个电台。因为这是无法实现的
not an issue there, All right, so an MVC like this, though,
没有一个问题,所以MVC,不过,
所以不会成为我们考虑的问题。然而，这样的一个 MVC
really is not, like your whole app isn't one big MVC,
真的不是,喜欢你的整个应用程序并不是一个大的MVC,
不可能代表你整个程序，它不会只是一个大的 MVC
Each MVC controls either one screen on an iPhone or
每一个屏幕在iPhone或MVC控制
每个 MVC 只会控制屏幕上的一个部分
maybe even a subpart of a screen on an iPhone or
甚至iPhone屏幕上或组成部分
甚至只会是屏幕上的一小部分
an iPad, Maybe there's two or
iPad,也许有两个或两个
有可能 iPhone 或 iPad 上
three MVCs controlling what's going on on the screen, so
三个mvc控制在屏幕上正在发生的事情,所以
一个屏幕同时有两三个 MVC 来控制
how do we build a big app? An app, you know,
我们如何建立一个大型应用程序?
那我们如何构建一个大型项目呢？
it's building an Instagram app, I gotta have MVCs for
这是构建一个Instagram应用程序,我需要mvc
比如 Instagram 这种图片社交程序
posting, I gotta have MVCs for image editing so
帖子,我需要mvc图像编辑
我需要发图片的 MVC，我需要编辑图片的 MVC
I can do my sepia tone, I gotta have an MVC for
我能做的深褐色的语气,我需要的MVC
加个棕褐色的怀旧滤镜。我还需要一个 MVC
scrolling through the latest posts that are coming up,
滚动的最新的帖子,
让我通过滑动查看最新发布的内容
I mean, I need all kinds of MVCs, How do these things, how
我的意思是,我需要各种各样的mvc,这些东西,怎么怎么做
我想说的就是我们需要各种各样的 MVC
do we combine them together? Well, looks like this,
我们把它们组合到一起呢?
这些 MVC 是如何协同工作的呢？实际上看起来是这样的
MVCs, when other MVCs point to them, it's always as
mvc,当其他mvc指向他们,总是
当一个 MVC 指向另一个 MVC 的时候
part of another MVC's view, So look at the three
另一个MVC的视图,看看这三个
被指像的那个会被作为当前 MVC 的视图
MVCs that are down here in the lower right corner,
mvc是在右下角,
看这里右下角的三个 MVC
You see these three MVCs? See this MVC up here, this purple
你看到这三个mvc吗?
看到这三个了吗？看到上面中间的这个紫色的控制器了吗？
one? Look how it points to them as if they were part of
一个?
它就是通过像连接自己视图一样指向这些 MVC
its view, You see that? There are no other arrows that point
它的视图中,您看到了吗?
看到了吗？这里所有的箭头
from one controller to another MVC except for
从一个控制器来另一个MVC除外
其中从一个控制器到另一个控制器的那些
that goes through this view side of the MVC,
通过这个视图的MVC,
无一不是通过视图这边连接的
Let me help you make that more concrete why that is,
让我帮你做更具体的原因,
我再具体解释为什么是这样
Let's say I had an app and it was a calendar app, and it was
假设有一个应用程序,这是一个日历应用程序,它是
比如我有一个日历程序
showing me the year, okay, a whole year's worth of my
告诉我,好的,我一整年的
展示了整整一年，一年里所有的日期
calendar entries, Well, on a tiny screen it's barely gonna
日历条目,在小屏幕上几乎要
对于比较小的屏幕来说，很难让它
be able to show me the 12 months, let alone the days and
可以给我12个月,更不用说天了
展示十二个月里全部的日子和其它内容
the things, right? So it's got this picture of the months,
的事情,对吧?
所以我选择只显示每个月
So that's a year MVC, let's say, in my calendar app, So
这是一年MVC,比方说,在我的日历应用程序,所以
这就是这个日历应用里负责每一年的 MVC
I click on one of the months cuz I want some more detail,
我点击一个月因为我想要一些更多的细节,
如果我需要更多细节，就点对应的月份
And now that year MVC moves out of the way and
现在那一年和MVC的移动方式
这个时候每年的 MVC 就隐藏了
puts up an MVC that's showing all the days of a month, okay?
提出一个显示所有的MVC的日子一个月,好吗?
同时换上显示这个月每一天的 MVC
Well, that month MVC, which is a totally separate MVC,
这月MVC,这是一个完全独立的MVC,
这个负责每个月的 MVC 和之前的是完全分开的
do you see how it's part of the year MVC's view?
你看到它是如何MVC的视图的一部分吗?
可以看出为什么是作为年这个 MVC 的视图了吗？
Because the year MVC is showing months,
因为今年MVC显示几个月,
因为每年里会展示这些月份
You wanna look at it, it's trying to zoom in on it,
你想看它,它试图放大,
你会在看了之后尝试放大到每个月的视图
it does it with another MVC, And same thing, in the month,
它与另一个MVC,同样的事情,在这个月,
这是通过另一个 MVC 实现的。同理，在每个月里
if I click on a day, the month MVC's gonna move out of
如果我点击一天,本月MVC会搬出
如果我点具体一天，负责那个月的 MVC 就消失了
the way, Put a day MVC that shows me all my appointments,
的方式,把一天的MVC显示我所有的约会,
换成现实当天日程的 MVC
for a day and that day MVC would be part of the view of
一天,那一天MVC视图的一部分
这个每一天的 MVC 又是那个月 MVC 的视图
the month MVC, okay, make sense? So that's why,
本月MVC,好的,有意义吗?
我说的有道理吧？这就是为什么
that's the only relationship we have between MVCs is across
这是唯一的mvc之间的关系
MVC 间的关系只会是
this view boundary, Now there can be other communication,
这个视图边界,现在可以有其他交流,
作为另一个的视图。我们再看看其它种类的通信
however, Look right here,
然而,看这里,
比如看这里
This MVC, the purple one in the top middle there,
这个MVC,紫色一个在顶部,
这个上面中间的紫色控制器
it's communicating to a model that is the same model as some
它的通信模型,一些是相同的模型
它联系的模型和另一个 MVC 是相同的
other MVC, So MVCs can share the same model, That's
其他MVC,MVC可以共享相同的模型,
也就是 MVC 之间可以共享模型
perfectly fine, The models are completely UI independent,
非常好,模型UI是完全独立的,
这是允许的，因为模型不会和 UI 挂钩
They don't care how many MVCs are looking at them, okay?
他们不在乎有多少mvc看着他们,好吗?
因此并不会介意被多个 MVC 共享
Cuz they don't even know about controllers,
因为他们甚至不知道控制器,
它们也不了解具体的控制器
Right, they're completely independent of that,
对的,他们是完全独立的,
所以也是能保持独立的
Also notice these two models down at the bottom,
还请注意这两个模型在底部,
还要注意这下面的两个模型
they're talking to each other, That's okay, too, because
他们相互交谈,没关系,,因为
它们在相互传递信息。这也是可以的
a model can be defined any way it wants, It's UI independent,
一个模型可以定义任何它想要的,它的UI独立,
因为模型想怎么实现就怎么实现，和 UI 不相关
it can talk to other models, whatever,
它可以与其他模型,无论如何,
所以能够联系其它模型
Now of course, it's still gonna wanna radio broadcast if
当然,它仍然会想无线电广播
当然，如果模型的内容会发生改变
maybe this model changes something in it, But
也许这模型变更,但是
还是要通过“电台”通知
it still can talk directly to the model, so
这样模型,还可以直接对话
同时直接联系当然是可以的
that's the other communication that can happen, But
这是可能发生的其他沟通,但是
这就是最后一种沟通的方式
no other communication can happen,
没有其他通信可以发生,
除此以外就没有了
We do not want our apps to look like this, Okay,
我们不希望我们的应用程序是这样的,好吧,
我们不希望程序最后变成这样
we've got these MVCs, and look, see this view over here?
我们有这些mvc,看,看到这一观点呢?
我们有一团 MVC。看这里的这个视图
It's talking to a different controller, This controller is
这是与不同的控制器,这个控制器
它在和不同的控制器通信
talking directly to another one, not out of view, but
直接说另一个,而不是视图,但是
这个控制器不是通过视图
just off to this side, You don't want this mess, If you
只是这一边,你不想要这个烂摊子,如果你
而是直接操作另一个控制器。你不会想要这样的乱局
do this mess, you really, you're not even doing an MVC,
做这个烂摊子,你真的,你连做一个MVC,
如果最后变成了这样，其实你是没有使用 MVC 的
Cuz everybody's in the same camp,
因为每个人都在同一阵营,
因为没有分工，都在一个阵营里
they're all just talking to each other,
他们都只是交谈,
想说就说，为所欲为
okay? So this is a no-go, And, of course,
好吧?
所以这是不被允许的
I'll be showing you, not next week, but the week after,
下周我将向您展示,而不是,但一周后,
我会在再下一周展示
how we build these connections between MVCs, For the first
我们如何构建这些mvc之间的连接,第一
如何建立 MVC 之间的联系
two weeks, we're just gonna focus on building one MVC,
两个星期,我们要专注于构建一个MVC,
我们前两周的时间，只会用到一个 MVC
our calculators, one MVC, But
我们的计算器,一个MVC,但是
我们的计算器只是一个 MVC
we're gonna add another MVC to our calculator in week three,
我们要添加另一个MVC计算器在三周,
第三周的时候再加入另一个 MVC
And you're gonna see, that's how we wire these things up,
你会看到,这就是我们线这些东西,
然后你就知道如何把它们链接起来了
okay? So that's MVCs, We're gonna dive back into
好吧?
MVC 就讲完了
continuing our calculator demo here, Again,
继续我们的计算器演示,
我们继续完成计算器
this is a slide you're gonna look at later and
这是一个幻灯片你要看之后
同样的，这一页是给你们之后看的
say, did I learn all these things? I hope so,
说,我学习所有这些东西吗?
问问自己是否学会了。我希望是的
And I'm not going back to these slides,
我不会回到这些幻灯片,
我准备现在把课件放完
So let me talk about what's coming up, On Friday, we have
让我谈谈接下来会发生什么,在周五,我们有
所以讲讲接下来几节课的内容
this debugging Friday session, I still don't have a room for
这个星期五调试会话,我仍然没有一个房间
星期五是讲调试，我还没有找到教室
it, but it will be announced on Piazza,
它,但它将宣布在广场,
找到后会在 Piazza 上通知
It's gonna be around noon, maybe 1 o' clock,
它会在中午,也许1 o '时钟,
课程大概在中午的时候吧，也许是下午一点
maybe 11, I know some of you have conflicting things
也许11,我知道你们中的一些人有冲突的事情
或者是上午十一点。我知道你们那个时候都很忙
in that time and might not be able to make it,
在此期间,可能无法使
很有可能没法来上课
It's optional, I hope you're all able to make it, however,
它是可选的,我希望你们都可以,但是,
这是选修课，不过我还是希望你们能尽量参加
We'll also in that one, be going over some like Xcode
我们也会在,会在一些像Xcode
不过我们还会讲些 Xcode 里常用的快捷键
shortcuts, how to get around in Xcode a little more easily,
快捷方式,如何规避在Xcode中更容易,
如何更便捷地使用 Xcode
Cuz I always end up clicking on everything, so
因为我总是点击结束一切,所以
我总是通过点击操作
you can see what I'm doing, But
你可以看到我在做什么,但是
好让你们看清我在干什么
there's command keys you can do to really master Xcode, And
有命令键你可以真正掌握Xcode和
不过你可以掌握 Xcode 提供的快捷键
then don't forget Monday's a holiday, so
不要忘记周一假日,所以
星期一放假
don't show up here,
别在这里出现,
你们不要跑来上课
And then next Wednesday, the reading assignment I
然后下个星期三,我阅读作业
下周三，要完成我星期一布置的阅读作业
assigned on Monday, plus the programming assignment that
安排周一,加上编程任务
以及编程作业
I just put on Piazza today, are both due
我把今天在广场,都是由于
我今天才放上 Piazza 的那个
next Wednesday, And then next Wednesday, you'll get another
下星期三,然后在下周三,你会得到另一个
下周三两个都要交。下周三
reading assignment and another programming assignment,
阅读作业,另一个编程任务,
我还会布置另一个阅读作业和编程作业
which will be due a week later, okay? Okay,
这将是由于一个星期后,好吗?
再下周交，好吧
here we go, back to our calculator, here's where,
好了,回到我们的计算器,在这里,
好了，可以开始编计算器了
exactly where we left off right here, And as I said when
哪里我们离开这里,当我说时
这是我们之前讲到的地方
we were there, this is a great little calculator,
我们在那里,这是一个很棒的小计算器,
之前说这个计算器看起来不错
it's nice, But it's kind of bad that this code right here,
这很好,但有点糟糕,这个代码,
只不过金玉其外，败絮其中
which is the what of this calculator, what is this?
这个计算器的什么,这是什么?
主要是这部分实现计算器功能的代码
This is a calculator, Here's the calculations happening,
这是一个计算器,计算发生,
这是什么？一个计算器，由这里完成计算
That really needs to be in a different camp,
真的需要在一个不同的阵营,
这应该放到另一个阵营里
It can't be in the controller like this, So that's the main
它不可能在这样的控制器,这是主要的
并不应该放在控制器中。所以我们主要的内容
thing we're gonna do in this demo right here,
我们要做的事情在这个演示,
也就是我们今天要完成的是
is we're gonna create a model for
我们要创建一个模型吗
给这个计算器
this calculator,
这个计算器,
创建一个模型
where we're gonna put all this calculation,
我们要把这些计算,
负责所有的计算
And then we're gonna make this model really powerful and
然后我们会让这个模型真的很强大
然后我们要把这个计算器编的很强大
extensible as you'll see, So,
可扩展您将看到,所以,
同时可高度定制
we need to create a new data structure for our model, and
我们需要为我们的模型,创建一个新的数据结构
我们控制器需要一个新的数据结构
we do that with File > New > File,
我们使用File > New >文件,
所以通过菜单栏中的 File > New > File
Any time we wanna create a new class or new structure or
任何时候我们想要创建一个新的类或新结构
任何时候我们想要新建一个类，结构体
any kinda new data structure, this is what we do,
任何新的数据结构,这是我们做的,
或是其它数据类型的时候，我们都这样新建一个文件
So we hit this, it's gonna be a Swift File right here,
所以我们点击这个,它会迅速文件在这里,
我们点这个 Swift File
We'll look at it, maybe one or two of these others,
我们来看看它,也许一两个,
我们也许会用到这些
actually we probably won't even look at those,
实际上我们甚至可能不会看那些,
其实基本上不会用到
It's almost always gonna be a Swift File that you create
这是几乎总是会迅速创建的文件
我们基本都会选 Swift File
here, Here it is, it wants to know the name, So this is
这里,在这里,它想要知道这个名字,这是
点 Next 之后问你文件的名字
the brain of my calculator, right, the guts of it,
计算器的大脑,它的勇气,
因为它是计算器的“大脑”，内部结构
So I'm gonna call this CalculatorBrain, That's gonna
所以我要调用这个计算器大脑的
所以叫做 CalculatorBrain
be the name of the data structure that I'm gonna use
的名字我要使用的数据结构
我们把它作为这个数据结构的名字
here, And I'm gonna make sure I put it in the same group,
在这里,我要确保我把它放在同一组,
确认我下面选择把它放在
down here, as all the rest of my
下面,我所有的其余部分
和其它文件同一个 Group 中
classes like ViewController, see that ViewController,swift?
类像ViewController、看到ViewController迅速?
比如 ViewController，看到 ViewController.swift 了吗？
I'm gonna put it in the same place there,
我要把它放在同一个地方,
我要把它们放在一起
All right, so here it is on the left and right,
好吧,这是左和右,
好了，一左一右
actually, let's just make it fill the whole screen,
实际上,我们先把它填满整个屏幕,
还是隐藏 Assistant Editor 好了，全屏
If we look in the navigator, now we have three files,
如果我们看在navigator,现在我们有三个文件,
如果我们看这里的导航面板，现在就有三个文件了
okay, there's our controller, there's our view, and
好的,这就是我们的控制器,我们的观点,
ViewController 是控制器，Storyboard 负责视图
there's our model, MVC, voila, okay, it's that easy, Now,
我们的模型,MVC,瞧,好吧,那就是容易,现在,
最后是模型。MVC，看吧，就这么简单
we need (in this model) to think a little bit about what its
我们需要在这个模型中考虑一下它
要好好想想这个模型应该包含哪些公共 API
public API is, In other words, what does this model allow
公共API,换句话说,这个模型允许
公共接口，也就是这个模型允许其它人
other people, like controllers,
其他人,如控制器,
比如控制器
to do? Okay, that's one of the most fundamental things that
做什么?
实现的操作。最基础的部分
you wanna do whenever you're doing design,
你想当你做设计,
你设计数据结构的时候都要考虑的
Just think about what the public API, does everyone know
只是想想公共API,大家都知道
设计好公共接口。大家都知道什么是应用程序编程接口吗？
what API means? Application programming interface,
API意味着什么吗?
Application Programming Interface，API
It's all the methods and properties, Snd so
它的所有方法和属性,先期
即所有的方法和属性
your public API is the methods and properties you're gonna
你的公共API是你要的方法和属性
public API，公共的接口是
allow other classes or other data structures to access,
允许其他类或其他数据结构访问,
你允许其它类和结构体访问的方法和属性
So we really, really wanna think about that, Quickly also
所以我们真的,真的要想想,也很快
所以我们要好好考虑
notice that we've imported Foundation here, not UIKit,
注意,我们进口的基础,不是UIKit,
注意到这里是 import Foundation，而不是 UIKit
because this is not going to be a UI class, right? This
因为这不是一个UI类,对吧?
因为这不会是和 UI 相关的类
is UI independent, this is the model, Now I could say here,
是UI独立,这是模型,现在我可以说,
这是模型，是独立于用户界面的。我在这里可以写
okay, let's create a class called CalculatorBrain, Nope,
好的,让我们创建一个类称为计算器大脑不,
class CalculatorBrain，创建一个类
not Brian, brain, So I could do that, but I'm actually not
布莱恩,大脑,所以我可以这样做,但我不是
打错了，是 Brain，不是 Brian。我可以这么做
going to do that, I'm gonna use a different data structure
要这样做,我将使用一个不同的数据结构
但我不会这么做。因为我会使用另一种数据类型
here than a class, all right? I'm gonna use a struct, Now,
这里比一个类,对吧?
不是 class（类）而是 struct（结构体）
you're probably used to using struct in other languages, but
你可能习惯使用结构体在其他语言中,但是
你可能在其它语言中使用过结构体
you probably think of it as just like a little collection
你可能认为它就像一个小的收集
认为那就是个集合
of other variables is a struct, In Swift,
其他变量是一个结构体,迅速、
包含了些其它的变量
struct is a first class citizen,
结构体是一等公民,
在 Swift 中 struct 是一等公民
very much like the class, okay? And I'm gonna talk about
很像,好吗?
和 class 是差不多的
the difference between that in a second, And in fact,
在第二个的区别,事实上,
我马上会讲到底有什么区别
most of the commonly used classes in Swift are structs,
最迅速的常用类结构、
事实上 Swift 里常用的“类”其实都是结构体
like string, double, array, dictionary,
如字符串、双数组,字典,
比如 String，Double，Array，Dictionary
these are all structs, they're not classes, So
这些都是结构,它们不是类
都是结构体，不是类
what's the difference between a struct and a class?
什么是结构体和类的区别?
那结构体和类的区别在哪里呢？
I'm gonna talk in detail about it next week, but
下周我将详细讨论,但是
我下周会详细说明
I'm gonna tell you two important differences,
我要告诉你两个重要的差异,
但接下来会先说说两个重要区别
the two most important differences,
两个最重要的差异,
非常重要的区别
One thing, classes have inheritance,
类有继承,有一件事
第一个，类是可以继承的
structs do not, okay? So if you're building
结构不?
但结构体不行。所以如果你想
something that you think is gonna need to be sub classed
你认为需要的子分类
构造一个能扩展的对象
to be extensible, you probably wanna make it a class, I'm
是可扩展的,你可能想要把它一个类,我
就必须用类
gonna make my CalculatorBrain extensible in a different way
将计算器大脑可扩展的方式不同
我用其它方式扩展 CalculatorBrain
as you'll see, so
如您所见,
如你马上所见的
it doesn't need to be a class, I could possibly change
它不需要一个类,我可能会改变
所以我没有使用类。如果我稍后改变主意
it back to a class if I change my idea later, but
它返回一个类如果我改变我的想法之后,但是
可以随时改为类
my current architecture does not need to be sub classed,
我目前的架构不需要子分类,
但我当前的结构不需要 CalculatorBrain 的子类
so that's one difference, The other difference,
这是一个差异,其他差异,
这是其一。另外一个区别
huge difference, and
巨大的差异,
本质的区别
the one that's gonna take the most getting used to for
的最适应需要
也是你需要理解的概念
you conceptually, is that classes live in the heap, and
你从概念上讲,这类活在堆中,
类存储在堆中
you have pointers to them, Structs do not live in
你有指针,结构不生活在
通过指针传递。结构体存储在栈上
the heap, and they are passed around by copying them, okay?
堆,传递通过复制它们,好吗?
通过拷贝值传递
We call the copying style value types,
我们所说的复制样式值类型,
我把拷贝值传递叫值类型
We call the, in the heap file, style, reference types,
我们所说的,在堆中文件,风格,引用类型,
存储在堆中的方式叫引用类型
Because we have a reference to them in the class case,
因为我们班上有一个参考的情况下,
类通过引用来使用
we actually copy them around in the struct case,
我们复制他们在结构的情况下,
而结构体需要拷贝值使用
Now, you know, that might seem like a big restriction,
现在,你知道,这可能看起来像一个大的限制,
那看起来，使用结构体会有很大的限制
I gotta copy these things around, what if they're big?
我要复制这些事情,如果他们大吗?
结构体很大的时候，也会拷贝吗？
But as I mentioned on Monday, these things are passed around
周一,但正如我所提到的,这些东西都是传递
星期一提到的，凡是通过拷贝值传递的
copy on right, So when you pass them around, if you don't
在正确的拷贝,所以当你通过他们,如果你不
都会采用“写时复制”，也就是如果
actually change them, then no copy is actually made, Okay,
实际上改变它们,那么实际上是由没有副本,好吧,
没有改变它的值，那么是不会进行拷贝的
but it's all behind the scenes for you, all right?
但这都是在幕后,好吗?
这些都是在内部自动完成的
So that's a huge difference,
这是一个巨大的差异,
这就是本质的差别
Now why would I want my CalculatorBrain to be a struct
为什么我想要计算器大脑结构
为什么我会把 CalculatorBrain 定义为结构体而不用类呢？
instead of a class? Well, I don't imagine I'm gonna have
而不是一个类?
因为我想象不到会有
a whole bunch of different people referencing it,
一大堆不同的人引用它,
其它地方需要引用它
The CalculatorBrain is a brain for an MVC,
MVC的计算器大脑是一个大脑,
CalculatorBrain 是 MVC 的核心
So that MVC is gonna access it, but I, I don't see a lot
MVC将访问它,但是我,我没有看到很多
所以 MVC 会访问它，除此之外
of other entities somehow trying to point to this thing,
其他实体不知怎么想的,
没有其它实体会尝试引用它
So I don't really need to be reference type,
所以我真的不需要引用类型,
所以我不需要引用类型
okay, I can have it be a value type from that standpoint, So
好吧,我可以是一个值类型的角度来看,
基于这点，我使用值类型
it's probably fine, Also it's a great opportunity for
它也可能很好,这是一个伟大的机会
而且这是个很好机会
me to show you what it looks like to make a struct because
我向你们展示一个结构,因为它是什么样子
让我展示如何使用结构体
making a struct looked almost just like being a class,
做一个struct看起来几乎就像被一个类,
像使用类一样使用结构体
but there's a couple minor differences,
但是有一些细微的差别,
但多多少少还是有些区别的
which you're gonna see real soon here, okay?
很快,你会看到的,好吗?
你很快就会知道
So now back to the public API,
所以现在回到公共API,
OK，回到 public API（公共接口）
what is the public API of this? Well, I know that
这的公共API是什么?
这里需要定义什么公共接口呢？
this CalculatorBrain is gonna need a func that performs
这个计算器并用是需要执行的函数
我知道 CalculatorBrain 需要一个方法来执行数学计算
operation, Okay, for sure because that's fundamentally
操作,因为这是根本
这是最基本的要求
what it does, It performs an operation, And we'll use
它做什么,它执行一个操作,我们将使用
它需要执行数学计算
the same mechanism we used on Monday to define it,
相同的机制我们周一用于定义它,
我们用周一使用的方式来定义它
I will have some mathematical symbol be the thing that
我将有一些数学符号的东西
我会通过数学符号
defines what operation we're performing, okay? And notice
定义了我们执行什么操作?
来判断需要执行什么计算
that I made the external name be blank, It's a close call
我做外部的名字是空白,这是千钧一发
注意，这里实参标签（argument label）为空
here as whether you would want it to be symbol,
在这里你是否想要的象征,
但你可能觉得实参标签叫 symbol 更好
In other words, would I call performOperation like this,
换句话说,我叫performOperation中像这样,
或者说，我会这样调用 performOperation
okay, performOperation(symbol, whatever, Or
好的,performOperation中(象征,无论如何,或
performOperation(symbol: XXXXX)
whether I want it to be blank, and I say performOperation,
我是否想要一片空白,我说performOperation中,
相比之下，我觉得留空更好，我会这样读 performOperation
and I just put the string, the symbol in here like pi or
我只是把字符串,在这里像π或象征
然后把像 pi 或者其它符号放进去
whatever, It's a close call here,
无论如何,这是一场势均力敌的电话,
这更贴近调用的意思
this is a close judgement call as to which is better,
这是一个接近判断调用哪个更好,
很容看出哪种调用方式更好
I'm gonna go with this because I think reading this code,
我要用这个,因为我认为阅读这段代码,
我会保留这样，因为我觉得代码更通顺易读
performOperation pi makes perfect sense to me,
performOperation中π对我意义非凡,
performOperation("π") 读起来更通顺
Adding the word symbol in there doesn't really
添加这个词没有真正象征
在这里增加 symbol 字符作为实参标签
make it any clearer to me, so
我让它更清楚,所以
并没有提高可读性
that's the way I'm gonna go with this one, Okay,
这就是我要用这个,好吧,
所以我选择这样写
what else do I need? Well, if you're performing operations,
我需要什么?
OK，接下来还要做什么？很明显，如果要执行计算
you have to have operands to perform one, right?
你必须执行一个操作数,对吧?
就必须要一个操作数
If you're doing square root,
如果你做的平方根,
如果要执行平方根
you have to do square root of something, whatever, So
你要做根,不管,所以
那么你必须对某个操作数执行平方根
I'm gonna have to have some func that sets the operand as
我要有一些函数,设置操作数
所以我必须定义一个方法来设置操作数
well, okay? And again, I'm gonna have no external name,
好吧,好吧?
参数这里依然没有实参标签
and we'll call it the operand, And I'm gonna have my
我们会称它为操作数,我要有我
形参名称（parameter name）叫 operand
entire CalculatorBrain work in doubles, It's
整个的计算器大脑工作双打,这是
我让整个 CalculatorBrain 都使用 double（浮点类型）
gonna be a double precision CalculatorBrain, so I'm gonna
将双精度的计算器大脑,所以我将
所以 CalculatorBrain 是浮点精度的
have the operand be a double, Now, here's a case where I
操作数是一个双,现在,这里有一个情况吗
所以我定义 operand 也是浮点类型
definitely know that I don't wanna have an external name,
肯定知道我不想有一个外部的名字,
这里我也没有定义实参标签
because saying setOperand (operand: 5,0), that's
因为说setOperand(操作数:5,0),这是
因为 setOperand(operand: 5.0) 并不通顺
ridiculous, that's completely redundant, don't need it,
荒谬,完全是多余的,不需要它,
有点累赘，完全是多余的，所以不需要
It's very clear, if I do this, setOperand(5,0),
很明显,如果我这样做,setOperand(5,0),
setOperand(5.0) 更容易理解
That's clear what I'm talking about, So no question in my
很清楚我在说什么,所以我没有问题
而且读起来也更通顺，我觉得
mind that that's better, And then you set the operand,
注意,这是更好的,然后你设置操作数,
这样更好。然后这里设置 operand
you perform operations, guess what? You gotta
你执行操作,你猜怎么着?
执行了某个运算，然后呢？
get the result, Now, I could have a func to getResult or
得到的结果,现在,我可以有一个func getResult或
你需要一个方法来获取计算结果。我可以定义一个方法
something like that, That returns a double, right?
这样,返回一个双,对吗?
像 getResult 之类的，返回的是浮点类型
That's one thing I do, But that's really not very Swift,
这是我做的一件事,但真的不是很迅速,
就像这样，但不推荐在 Swift 这么做
Really in Swift what you would do is you say, here's a result
在斯威夫特你所要做的是你说,这是一个结果
在 Swift 里，最好这样，定义一个 result 变量
var, that returns result, Now the only problem with that UI,
var,返回结果,现在唯一的问题,UI,
这就是计算返回的结果。唯一要注意的是
or that API rather, is I don't want anyone to set my result,
或API,而我不希望任何人把我的结果,
对于这个 API（应用程序接口），我不希望其它人能修改结果
I'm the calculator brain, I calculate the result, So
我大脑计算器,计算结果
结果应该计算器来计算
this needs to be read-only,
这需要只读的,
所以要定义这个变量为只读
Anyone remember how we can make a var read-only?
谁记得我们如何做一个var只读?
有谁知道怎么设置变量为只读？
No? Someone suggest let, And that's kinda
没有?
没人知道吗？有人说用 let
not exactly what let does, Let makes it to constant,
不是什么让,让让它不变,
用 let 有点不太准确。因为 let 定义的是常量
meaning that it's read-only, But it can only set once,
这意味着它是只读的,但它只能设置一次,
虽然也是只读，但 let 只能在定义的时候赋值
Whereas result is constantly changing, So we can't do let,
而结果是不断变化的,所以我们不能做,
计算结果需要不断变化，所以不能用 let
unfortunately, But it's a really good guess,
不幸的是,但它是一个很好的猜测,
但这是个好想法
Actually we do it with the computed property thing, Okay,
实际上我们做计算属性的东西,好吧,
实际上可以使用 computed property（计算型属性）
remember we computed that display value and
记得我们计算和显示值
记得之前定义 displayValue 变量的
we had get and set? Well, we just don't do the set, right?
我们已经获取和设置?
get 和 set 属性吗？只要去掉 set 就可以了
In this case we're just not gonna do, Just not put that on
在这种情况下,我们不只是要做的,不是把它
在这里，把 set 去掉，留下 get
there, Boom, this is a read-only property,
繁荣,这是一个只读属性,
这就是只读属性
Everybody got that? It's like currentTitle on button,
大家都明白了吗?
就像 button 的 currentTitle 属性
It's get only, All right now,
现在只能得到,所有,
也是只读的。接下来
I'm gonna think a little bit about the internal
我要想一下内部
在使用之前，我需要考虑下
implementation of this before I go and start using this
实现在我走之前,开始使用这个
这里内部如何实现
thing, I know that a calculator brain, internally,
的事情,我知道一个计算器的大脑,在内部,
我知道计算器内部
it kind of accumulates its answer as it's going, And
它的回答会累积到一定程度,和
需要保存计算的结果
so I'm actually gonna have an internal var, and watch this,
所以我要有一个内部的var,看这个,
所以我定义一个私有变量，看这里
private var, I'm gonna call it accumulator, I'm
私人var,我会叫它蓄电池,我
private var（私有变量），命名为 accumulator
gonna make it a double, okay? So this is gonna be internal,
要使它成为一个双,好吗?
类型为 double（浮点类型）。这是一个私有变量
So now, other people can't access this,
现在,其他人无法访问,
其它外部成员无法访问它
That's what private means, And for all your homeworks for
这就是私人的意思,你所有的作业
这就是私有的含义。在这季的所有作业里
this entire quarter, I want you to put private in front of
整个季度,我想让你把私人的面前
我希望你在所有你认为是内部使用的变量前
things that you think are internal implementation,
什么东西你认为是内部实现,
都增加 private 关键字
To any class you've create in this, in this course, okay?
在这你创建任何类,在本课程中,好吗?
任何本课程中写的代码都这么做
So get used to doing that, It's very important,
所以习惯了这样做,这是非常重要的,
要成为一种习惯，这很重要
These three are not private, They're public,
这三个都不是私有的,这些画是公开的。
这三个不是私有的，是公有的
I'm gonna allow other people to call these, But
我要让别人称这些,但是
其它外部成员可以访问调用它们
this one is internal, Now, one thing you notice is
这是内部的,现在,你注意到的一件事是
这个是内部私有的。有一点要注意
I don't have any error up here that says no initializer,
我没有任何错误在这里说没有初始化,
这里没有初始化，但没有提示任何错误
Remember that when I created a var in
还记得,当我创建了一个var
记得之前在 ViewController 中
the view controller,
视图控制器,
创建变量吗？
and it said that there's no initializers, And I had to
说没有初始化,我不得不
会抛出没有初始化的错误
make userInTheMiddleOfTyping equal false, Why don't
使userInTheMiddleOfTyping等于错误,为什么不
必须初始化 userInTheMiddleOfTyping 等于 false
I have to do it here? That's because this is a struct, And
我在这里有什么关系呢?
为什么这里不需要呢？这是因为这是结构体
structs automatically get an initializer,
结构自动初始化,
结构体会自动提供一个构造器
That will initialize all of their uninitialized vars,
将初始化所有的未初始化,var,
通过那个构造器来初始化所有未初始化的属性
okay? You get a free initializer,
好吧?
所以你并不需要自己提供一个构造器
You don't get that with class, Only with the structs, so
你不会用类,只与结构,所以
但在类中就不能这样做，只有结构体可以
there is one difference between class and structs,
类和结构体之间有一个区别,
这也是类和结构体的一个区别
So we're gonna have a struct, for CalculatorBrain, or
所以我们要有一个结构体,计算器大脑或
好，现在已经有个叫 CalculatorBrain 的结构体
an initializer for CalculatorBrain, That will
计算器大脑的初始值设定项
它自动提供的构造器
take a double and it'll initialize as accumulator,
双,蓄电池会初始化,
会通过浮点类型的参数来初始化 accumulator 变量
But actually, I don't wanna do that,
但事实上,我不想那样做,
但实际上，我并不希望它这么做
Because let me think of what is accumulator's initial value
因为我认为蓄电池的初始值是什么
我们真正想把 accumulator 初始化为什么？
really wanna be? When someone creates a CalculatorBrain,
真的想要吗?
当 CalculatorBrain 被创建的时候
I don't wanna have them to tell me what the accumulator's
我不想让他们来告诉我蓄电池的
我并不想知道 accumulator 变量的
initial value is,
初始值,
初始化值是多少
Because I know what the initial accumulator internally
因为我知道最初的蓄电池内部
因为我认为 accumulator
its initial value is when I start up, It's not set,
它的初始值是当我启动时,它不是,
在我使用之前是不应该有值的
So I'm gonna make this be an optional,
所以我要使这是一个可选的,
所以我把它的改为 optional（可选）类型
Do you see why I'm making that an optional?
你知道为什么我做出一个可选的吗?
知道为什么吗？
Because the accumulator when I create my brain, I haven't
由于蓄电池当我创建我的大脑,我没有
因为我在创建 CalculatorBrain 的时候
accumulated any result, So I'm in this not set state,
积累的任何结果,所以我在这没有设置状态,
accumulator 没有记录任何结果，所以它是缺省值的可选类型
So, it's a perfect opportunity to make this a double or
所以,这是一个绝佳的机会让这双
这是完美的解决方案，我可以在代码中把它设置为
an optional so I can express that in my code, All right? So
一个可选的所以我可以表达我的代码,对吧?
使用可选的浮点类型
if I have this internal accumulator right here,
如果我有这个内部蓄电池,
如果 accumulator 是私有的
how can I use that to implement these?
我如何用它来实现这些?
这些怎么实现呢？
Well, two of them are easy, Okay, setOperand
嗯,好的,setOperand,其中两个是容易
这两个地方都很容易实现
just sets the accumulator equal to that operand, Okay,
设置蓄电池等于操作数,好吧,
setOperand 方法只要设置 accumulator 等于入参 operand
cuz when you set a new operand to operate on,
因为当你设置一个新的操作数操作,
因为当你传入新的 operand 时
that replaces anything you have on your accumulator,
替换任何你对蓄电池,
就会覆盖掉 accumulator 的旧值
It's what you're now accumulating, So that, that
现在你的积累,所以,
这就是当前 accumulator 的值
could be any, any easier than that, And then we get results,
可以是任何,任何比这更容易,然后我们得到结果,
这很容易做到。当你获取 result
you're just gonna return the accumulator, Now,
你要返回蓄电池,现在,
你只要返回 accumulator 的值就可以了
we've got a couple of errors here that we
我们这儿有几个错误
我们看到这里提示有几个错误
have to deal with, What's this one right here?
必须处理,这个是什么?
需要我们处理。这一个是什么错误？
This looks perfectly fine, How could this be bad?
这看起来非常好,这怎么可能坏呢?
这看起来并没问题，为什么会出错呢？
Accumulator is an optional double, I'm setting it to
蓄电池是一个可选的两倍,我设置它
accumulator 是可选浮点类型
a double, It's gotta work, what's the problem?
双,这是必须的工作,是什么问题?
赋给它一个浮点类型。这应该是可以的，会有什么问题？
Says I cannot assign to this property, because self is
说我不能指定该属性,因为自我
这里提示 “I cannot assign to this property, because
immutable, Self meaning the calculator brain is immutable,
不可变的,自我即计算器大脑是不可变的,
self is immutable”。说因为 self 不能被修改
And it's saying, do you wanna fix this by making this method
这是说,你想解决这个问题,使这个方法
提示还说，如果你想修复这个错误
be mutating? You see he's trying to add this here,
是变异?
需要在该方法前增加 mutating。它已经提示这么做了
Another difference between structs and
另一个结构体和之间的区别
这是结构体和类的另一个区别
classes, if you have a method, okay? Or a property
类,如果你有一个方法,好吗?
如果你有一个方法，或者属性
that you're setting, that well, if you have a method and
你设置,,,如果你有一个方法
当你在某个方法内
it changes the value of this thing,
它改变了这个东西的价值,
修改它的值
you have to mark it mutating, You have to tell Swift, this
你必须标记变异,你必须告诉迅速、
必须加上 mutating 关键字。你必须要告诉 Swift
method can change the value of this struct, Why is that?
方法可以改变这个结构的值,这是为什么呢?
这个方法可以修改结构体的值。为什么会这样呢？
It's because of that copy on write thing, Remember,
因为文案写的东西,记住,
这和写时复制有关
I told you that structs are passed around by copying them,
我告诉你周围结构传递通过复制他们,
记得之前说过结构体通过拷贝传递
And when you write to them, then it copies it, So
当你写信给他们,然后复制它
但当发生修改时，才会实际进行拷贝
it has to know you're writing it by calling setOperand,
它必须知道它通过调用setOperand你写,
所以它必须知道你在调用 setOperand 修改了值
So, you have to make setOperand be mutating func,
因此,你必须使setOperand变异函数,
所以你必须为 setOperand 增加 mutating 关键字
So that's the difference between class and a struct,
这是类和结构体之间的区别,
这是类和结构体的区别
With that, what's this error down here? A different error,
,下面这个错误是什么?
下面还有一个不同的错误
Anyone know what this error is? Louder? Okay,
谁知道这个错误是什么?
谁知道这是什么错误？
the problem here is we're trying to return a double,
这里的问题是我们要返回一个双,
在这里，我们尝试返回浮点类型
an accumulator is an optional, Okay, so it's saying here,
一个累加器是一个可选的,所以说,
但 accumulator 是可选浮点类型，所以这里提示
hey unwrap this, Now, I do not wanna do this here, Okay,
嘿,打开这个,现在,我不想做这个,好吧,
没有解包，但我不想这么解包
because it's perfectly valid for the accumulator to be not
因为它是蓄电池不完全有效
因为这样的话，accumulator 就不能缺省可选值
set, In fact, this starts out not set, And in fact,
集,事实上,这个开始不是,事实上,
但实际上，accumulator 一开始就是缺省值的
I can think already of another case where the accumulator is
我可以认为已经累加器的另一个例子是
我能想到另一个例子，accumulator
gonna be not set, What if I say, five times three equals,
会不会,如果我说,五乘以三等于
会是缺省值。例如我要计算：“5 x 3 = ”
in my calculator? After I say five times,
在我的计算器?
当我输入“5 x”
my accumulator is not set right now,
我现在蓄电池没有设置,
的时候，accumulator 是缺省值的
Cuz I need the three equals until I can get the result, So
因为我需要三个=,直到我能得到结果,所以
因为我输入“3 =”时才会计算结果
my accumulator's often gonna be going back to not set,
我的蓄电池经常会回到没有设置,
所以 accumulator 经常变成缺省值的可选类型
When we're in that weird five times three equals five times,
当我们在那个奇怪的五乘以三等于五次,
在“5 x 3 =”中，输入“5 x”时
the accumulator's not set right now, Three, okay,
蓄电池不是现在,三,好吧,
accumulator 是缺省值的
the accumulator's set again, equals, okay,
蓄电池组,=,好吧,
输入“3”时，accumulator 有值了，输入“=”号
here's the result, Okay,
这里是结果,好吧,
就计算出结果了
so I can't have this be exclamation point,
所以我不能有一个感叹号,
所以这里不能有感叹号
Or this thing is gonna crash every time someone asks for
或者这个东西会崩溃每次有人问
这样的话，每次输入“5 x”的时候获取结果
the result after they say five times, So we can't have that,
结果他们说五次后,我们不可能,
程序就会崩溃，肯定不能这样
So instead, I'm going to turn result into an optional, And
所以,我要把结果变成一个可选的,和
所以取而代之的，把返回结果改为可选类型
that makes sense too,
这是有道理的,
这是有道理的
Because if someone using this object in the middle of five
因为如果有人使用这个对象在5
因为如果输入“5 x”时
times says, what's the results? It'll tell you it's
次说,结果是什么?
获取到的结果是什么？这里会返回缺省值
not set, because I'm in the middle of five times, right?
没有,因为我在五次,对吧?
因为还没执行计算
And in your homework, you're even gonna make it clearer to
在你的家庭作业,你甚至会使其更清晰
做作业的时候，你们尽量搞清楚
users of this why this might not be set, okay? So
为什么这个用户可能不是集合,好吗?
为什么这里会是缺省值
you'll see that, All right, so
好吧,那么,你会发现
你会明白的
that's a good start to the implementation of this thing,
这是一个很好的开始实施这个东西,
这是一个好的开始
But before we go into deeper in this implementation,
但是在我们进入更深层次的在这个实现中,
但在我们继续深入之前
let's go back to our controller and use this public
让我们回到我们的控制器,并使用这个公共
我们回到 controller，并使用
API that I just designed, Okay, I wanna use this,
API,我只是设计,好吧,我想用这个,
我们刚刚设计的公开应用程序接口。OK，用这里
So I'm gonna go back to my controller, Now,
所以我要回到我的控制器,现在,
回到 controller
I wanna have my controller and my model on screen on the same
我想有我的控制器和模型在屏幕上的相同
我希望 controller 和 model 并列在屏幕上
time, Just so I can see them side by side, And
时间,这样我可以看到他们肩并肩,和
我可以同时看到它们
the best way to do that is to bring out this assistant
最好的办法,是把这个助理
最好的方式是点一下这个 assistant editor
editor thing again, right? And you can go up to the top,
编辑器的事情,对吧?
然后选择最上方这里
And you can actually manually pick, Or
,或者您可以手动选择
然后手动选择
I'm gonna teach you one little Alt thing,
我要教你一个小Alt的事情,
或者我教你使用 Alt 快捷键
If you hold down Alt and click on some other file over here,
如果你按住Alt和其他一些文件,点击
如果你按住 Alt 键，并点击其它文件
you'll get that to appear on the right,
你会出现在右边,
Assistant Editor 会在右边打开它
So Alt-clicking means bring it up on the right,
所以Alt-clicking意味着把它的权利,
Alt + 点击操作意味着在右边打开它
Okay, so here I have my model on the left,
好吧,我这里有我的模型在左边,
现在左边打开了 model
And here I have my controller on the right,
在这里我有我的控制器在右边,
右边打开了 controller
So what I need to do now is fix this broken code that is
所以我现在需要做的就是解决这个破碎的代码
现在要做的就是修复代码
doing model stuff inside the controller by using the public
做模型通过使用公共控制器内的东西
把一些 controller 的逻辑替换成
API of my model, Now, notice that
我的模型的API,现在,请注意
调用 model 的应用程序接口。这里需要注意
touchDigit does nothing when it comes to calculating,
touchDigit没有计算时,
touchDigit 方法和计算过程无关
All it does is get the digits from the keyboard and
它所做的是把从键盘和数字
它只是把键盘输入的值
put them in the display, It's not doing any calculating, so
把它们放在显示器,它不做任何计算
显示到 display 上，它没有参与任何计算
we don't have to touch that,
我们不需要联系,
所以我们不用管它
Same thing here with this display value computed var,
同样的事情在这个显示值计算var,
这个 displayValue 变量也一样
All it's doing is converting
所有的转换
它只是负责转换类型
the display from a double to a string and
从双弦和显示
把 display 的值类型在浮点类型和字符串类型相互转换
back, That's all it does,
回来,,
它就只做这些
It has nothing to do with being a calculator,
它与一个计算器,
也没有参与到计算过程
That's just the UI for this particular calculator, So
这只是这个计算器的界面,所以
这些都是计算器的用户界面
the only thing we actually have to change is this method,
我们必须改变的唯一的事就是这个方法,
实际上我们只需要改动这个方法
performOperation, Now, we know that this part in here
performOperation中,现在,我们知道,这部分在这里
performOperation。现在，我们知道这部分代码
does not belong in here, And in fact, I'll throw it over
不属于这里,事实上,我将把它结束了吗
其实并不属于这里，我会把它丢到 model 里去
here in my model, Even though it's not gonna work there,
在我的模型,虽然它不会在那里工作,
尽管丢过去之后不能编译
But we'll throw it over there for now just to get it out of
但我们现在把它扔在那里的
但为了规范，还是先把它丢过去再说
the way, okay? So now we need to somehow use this
顺便说一下,好吗?
然后在这方法内部
API over here in this implementation, So,
API在这里在这个实现中,所以,
使用 model 的应用程序接口
let's look at all three parts of what has to do,
让我们看看这三个部分的,
我们需要修改 performOperation 方法
what we have to do in perform operation, First of all,
我们要做的在执行操作中,首先,
的三个地方。第一个
if we're in the middle of typing a number,
如果我们在输入一个数字,
如果输入某个数字的过程中开始计算
we need to set that number as an operand, okay?
我们需要设置这个数字作为操作数,好吗?
必须要把数字存成操作数
Because obviously, the user typing in a number and
因为很明显,用户数量和类型
因为很明显，用户输入一个数字
they perform an operation that number they were typing
他们执行一个操作数类型
然后执行计算，那么输入的数字
needs to be an operand, So, right off the bat here,
需要一个操作数,所以,马上在这里,
肯定是操作数，所以在这里
I'm gonna say, if the user is in the middle of typing,
我想说,如果用户在打字,
我会判断，如果用户在输入过程中计算
then I'm going to set the operand, Now, how do I
然后我要设置操作数,现在,我如何
那么我会把输入的值设置为操作数
communicate to my brain here? Where is my brain? [LAUGH] I
我的大脑在这里交流吗?
那我怎么和 CalculatorBrain 沟通呢？
don't have a var for my brain, So let's create a var, and
没有我的大脑的var,所以让我们创建一个var,
我需要，但又没有 CalculatorBrain 的实例，那就创建一个
it will be private, Because the model is almost always
这将是私人的,因为模型几乎总是
创建一个私有变量。因为在 controller 中，model 几乎
private to the controller, Cuz you don't want someone else
私人的控制器,因为你不想让别人
都是私有的，因为其它地方不会，你也不希望它们用到
reaching in and messing with this controller's model, So
达到在本控制器的模型和干扰,所以
controler 里面的 model 实例
I'm gonna make it a private var,
我将使它成为一个私有变量,
所以定义私有变量
I'm gonna call it brain, Its type is CalculatorBrain, okay?
我要叫它的大脑,它的类型是计算器大脑好吗?
变量名为 brain，类型为 CalculatorBrain
That's good, Now, as soon as I put this line of code in,
这很好,现在,当我把这行代码放进去,
很好，我刚写完这行代码
look what I get, The old, you don't have any initializers,
看看我,旧的,你没有任何初始化,
就提示有错误了：你需要构造器
That's because this is not initialized,
这是因为这不是初始化,
因为这里没有初始化
So I'm gonna initialize it by creating a CalculatorBrain,
所以我要初始化它通过创建一个计算器大脑
这里我通过构造一个 CalculatorBrain 来初始化
And you create a CalculatorBrain in exactly
你创建一个计算器并用
和创建类实例一样
the same way that you create as a class,
同样的方式,您创建一个类,
结构体也需要这么创建
With the name of the type and then the parentheses,
同类型的名称,然后括号,
名字，类型，然后是括号
Now we have no arguments in here, Because we have no
现在我们没有理由在这里,因为我们没有
这里没有参数，因为我们
uninitialized var, Since we made this be an optional,
未初始化的变量,因为我们这是一个可选的,
没有未初始化的变量，因为这里定义为可选的
it's initialized to nil automatically for us for free,
这是免费为我们自动初始化为零,
它默认会自动初始化为 nil
remember? So we have no uninitialized vars, so
还记得吗?
所以我们没有未初始化的变量
we just do open parentheses, closed parentheses, And
我们只做开括号,括号,关闭,
我们只需要左括号，右括号
of course, we don't need this type, right?
当然,我们不需要这种类型,对吗?
当然，这个类型也可以去掉
Because it gets inferred, So if we ask what type is this?
因为它被推断,所以如果我们问这是什么类型?
因为代码会自动推断类型。如果问这是什么类型？
It says, that's a calculator brain, Has to be cuz that's
它说,这是一个计算器,因为这是
代码会自动推断出是 CalculatorBrain 类型
what you set it to, All right, so now that we have a model,
你设置它,好吧,现在我们有一个模型,
现在在 controller 中已经实例化了 model
our controller, This is the green arrow, talking from our
我们的控制器,这是绿色箭头,从我们的谈话
这是绿色通道，连通
controller to the model, We can say, brain set your
控制器模型,我们可以说,大脑设置
controller 和 model。我们可以这样来使用
operand to be whatever the display value is, And
操作数是无论显示值,
brain.setOperand(displayValue)
of course now we are not in the middle of typing, so I'll
当然现在我们不是在打字,所以我
当然，用户已经没有在输入某个数字了
put that in here, So that's all we need to do to set
把它放在这里,这是我们需要做的
把这一行移上来。这就是设置
the brain's operand, We only need to do if these are in
大脑的操作数,我们只需要做这些
brain 操作数的步骤。只需要判断用户
the middle of typing something new,
输入新的东西,
是不是正在输入一个新值
and they hit an operation button,
他们打了一个操作按钮,
然后点击的运算符按钮
We need to give them that operand, okay?
我们需要给他们操作,好吗?
是我们就设置操作数为输入的值
Now, what about the stuff that was in here, okay?
现在,这里的东西是什么,好吗?
这一块怎么处理呢？
We get this mathematical symbol of the operation to do,
我们得到了这个数学符号的操作,
我们获取到了计算运算符号
Now I'm just gonna let the brain do it,
现在我要让大脑,
我需要通知 brain
So I'm just gonna say brain perform operation,
所以我想说大脑执行运算,
我只需要输入
the mathematical symbol, That's it,
数学符号,就是这样,
brain.performOperation(mathematicalSymbol)
I'm just handing that off to the model, Because that's,
我只是把这交给模型,因为这是,
我把这些都交给 model
this is not my job as a controller to do calculation,
这不是我的工作作为一个控制器进行计算,
因为计算不是 controller 的工作
Okay I'm a UI guy,
好吧我一个UI的家伙,
controller 属于用户界面
Now of course after the operation is done I need to
手术后当然是我需要完成的
在操作过后，我需要设置
set my display value equal to the brain's result,
设置我的显示值等于大脑的结果,
displayValue 等于 brain.result
But of course I can't do this because displayValue
当然,我不能这么做,因为displayValue
但我不能这么写，因为 displayValue
is a double, And the result, might be
是一个双,结果,可能吗
类型是浮点，但 brain.result
not set cuz it's an optional, So I'm gonna say here,
不是因为它是一个可选的,所以我要在这里说,
是可选类型，可能缺省值。所以这里需要写
if I can let the result equal the brain to results,
如果我可以让结果等于大脑的结果,
如果我可以让 result 等于 brain.result
In other words, if the brain's result is determined, Then I
换句话说,如果大脑的结果确定,然后我
换句话说，如果 brain.result 是有值的
will let the displayValue equal the result, That's it,
会让displayValue平等的结果,就是这样,
那么 displayValue 就等于这个值
Okay, so that little piece of code to input has completely
好了,这小段代码输入完全
OK，这一小段代码就可以把
taken all calculation out of the controller,
控制器的所有计算,
把计算模块分出去
And put you into this other camp the model,
把你变成另一阵营模型,
全权交给 model 处理
And now we can spend the rest of this lecture making this
现在我们可以度过余生的这节课做这个
剩下的时间我们都会构建这个
really powerful model,
真正强大的模型,
强大的 model
And nothing is gonna change over here,
什么也不会改变,
这边不会再有任何修改
I'm literally never gonna edit this code ever again, In fact,
我真的不会再编辑这个代码,事实上,
我基本上不会再修改这里的代码
I'm just gonna get it off the screen, And
我要让它从屏幕上消失,和
事实上我会隐藏它
we're gonna spend all of our time over here in the model,
我们会花费我们所有的时间在模型中,
我们把时间都花在 model 上
So, let's start by making kind of a really dirt simple
所以,让我们开始通过一种真正肮脏的简单
我们先简单处理下
implementation of performOperation here, Which
实现performOperation中,
实现 performOperation
is try to get this code that was already there to work,
把这段代码,已经工作,
让这些代码通过编译就行
And mostly, that's just a matter of changing the names,
主要是,这只是一种改变名称,
首先，需要修改名字
Because this argument is symbol,
因为这个论点是符号,
因为参数名是 symbol
not mathematical symbol, So, we'll do that,
没有数学符号,因此,我们将这样做,
不是 mathematicalSymbol
And instead of setting a display value cuz we're not in
而不是设置显示值因为我们不是
然后替换 displayValue
a UI any more,
UI,
因为已经不再处理用户界面了
Now we're just setting the accumulator to that double pi,
现在我们只是设置蓄电池双π,
现在要设置 accumulator 等于 pi
Right, and the same thing here we're setting the accumulator
对的,同样的事我们设置蓄电池
同样，这里也需要设置 accumulator
to be the square root of the accumulator, Okay,
蓄电池的平方根,好吧,
等于根号 accumulator
now this is a problem right here,
现在这是一个问题,
又报错了
This line, why? Accumulator is an optional,
这条线,为什么?
这里是为什么出错呢？accumulator 是可选类型
You can't take the square root of an optional, So I could say
你不能把一个可选的平方根,所以我可以说
你不能对一个可选类型开根号
for example, if let operand equal the accumulator,
例如,如果我们操作数等于蓄电池,
我会写，如果让 operand 等于 accumulator
So if my accumulator is set, then I can tap the accumulator
如果我蓄电池组,那么我可以利用蓄电池
也就是如果 accumulator 有值，我再让 accumulator
be the square root of the operand, okay? Now,
操作数的平方根,好吗?
等于操作数的平方根
we have another warning right here on both of these lines,
我们这里有另一个警告这两种线,
这两行还有另外的错误
Why do you think, does anyone know why this is? We seen it
你为什么认为,有人知道这是为什么吗?
谁知道为什么吗？
before, five minutes ago, This
五分钟前,这个
我们5分钟前遇到过的
modifies this CalculatorBrain, So this method,
修改这个计算器并用,所以这种方法,
这里修改了 CalculatorBrain 的私有变量
perfomOperation, also needs mutating in front of it,
perfomOperation,也需要变异在它面前,
所以 perfomOperation 方法需要增加 mutating 关键字
okay? So I'll fix that, add mutating,
好吧?
加上就好了，不报错了
Adding this mutating takes a little bit getting used to,
添加这个变异需要有点适应,
你有时候可能会忘记添加 mutating 关键字
But it's great because its compiler notices it, And it's
但它是伟大的,因为它的编译器通知它,和它
但没关系，因为编译器会提醒你
gonna always be reminding you to do that, So believe it or
要总是提醒你,所以相信它或
它一定会提醒你添加
not we now have an MVC version of this calculator and if we
我们现在没有这个计算器,如果我们的MVC版本
OK，不管你信不信，MVC 版的计算器已经写完了
run it should just work, All right,
运行它应该工作,好吧,
如果你运行它，它肯定会工作的
here we go, Let's see, 7, 8, that's still working,
好了,让我们看看,7,8,这仍然是工作,
我们来试试，7，8
Okay, that was in the controller, Pi, woah,
好吧,那是在控制器,π,哇,
controller 部分正常。试试 pi
that's working, It's going off to the model,
这就是工作,去模型,
正常工作着，值传递给 model 了
And this is actually executing, And it's causing
这实际上是执行,导致
实际执行的是这一行
the accumulator to get set to that double pi, And
双π的蓄电池组,和
把 accumulator 设置成 pi 的值
then flicking at the result and putting it in display, How
然后移动在显示结果,并把它,如何做
然后把结果显示到 display 上
about 81 square root, square root? All right, excellent,
约81根,根?
那么81开根，再开根呢？好的，没错
okay, So now we're starting in a place where exactly where we
好,现在我们开始在哪里我们的地方
我们代码恢复到了之前的可用状态
were before, But we split off all of our calculating code
之前,但我们分裂我们所有的计算代码
并且我们把负责计算的代码分离出到
into this little class right here, So this is
到这个小类,这是
这里的一小块
a great opportunity now to enhance this to the max,
现在一个很好的机会来提高最大,
这是我们优化这部分代码的好机会
So we are gonna use all kinds of cool, Swift stuff that you
所以我们会用各种各样的酷,迅速的东西
我们将会使用一些你从没见过的
probably did not see in other languages,
可能没有看到在其他语言中,
Swift 语言仅有的特性
To make this a much more extensible calculator,
使它更可扩展计算器,
让这个计算器更容易扩展
Cuz right now, man, if I wanna add more operations,
因为现在的人,如果我想添加更多的业务,
因为现在，如果我们要增加运算符
I just get this huge switch statement case, this case,
我刚刚得到这个巨大的switch语句的情况下,这种情况下,
我需要增加 switch 代码块，添加 case 声明
that case, I'm gonna have to do if let operand equals
这种情况下,我要做的,如果我们操作数=
而且每次我都必须要添加判断
accumulator every single time,
蓄电池每一次,
如果常量 operand 等于 accumulator 之类的
For the things that are unary operations like square root,
的东西一元操作,比如平方根,
而且这些只是想平方根之类的一元计算
Imagine when I have the binary case like five times three
想象当我有二进制情况下三个五倍
想象下，如果我有二元操作，像“5 x 3 =”
equals, I'm gonna have to do the figuring out how to deal
=,我要如何交易
我需要考虑怎么处理
with the times and the equals for every single case,
随着时代和等于每一个情况下,
单个计算中出现的乘称号和等于号
Forget it, I can't do that, I need to build an engine here,
忘记,我做不到,我需要构建一个引擎,
算了，想都别想。我需要的是构造一个计算引擎
That can deal with constants,
能够处理常量,
既可以处理常量
That can deal with these unary operations like square root,
能够处理这些一元操作,比如平方根,
又可以处理像开根号之类的一元计算
That can deal with binary operations like multiply and
能够处理二进制乘法和这样的操作
还可以处理像加减之类的
plus and things like that, Okay? So that's exactly what
+之类的东西,好吗?
二元计算。这是
we're going to do, We're going to enhance this model, Now,
我们要做的,我们要提高这个模型中,现在,
接下来要做的。我们继续优化我们的 model
as we do all this enhancement, we're not going to change it
当我们完成这些增强,我们不会改变它
所有的优化，都不会影响外部
externally at all, And so the controller will not change,
外部,因此控制器不会改变,
调用，controller 不需要任何修改
That's what's really cool about this, We can do our
这是很酷的,我们可以做我们的
这是非常酷的
model development independent of our UI,
模型开发独立于我们的UI,
在把用户界面的功能基本完成之后
Once we have the UI, that kind of does the basics, all right,
一旦我们有了UI,这种最基本的,好吧,
就可以脱离 UI 只修改 model 的内部实现了
So what are we going to do here? Let's focus first,
所以我们要做什么呢?
接下来我们要做什么呢？我们看这里
Let's get rid of this code, cuz we know that's a mess,
让我们摆脱这段代码,因为我们知道这是一团糟,
我们先去掉这些代码，因为这写得不好
We're not going to do that, Let's focus on constants,
我们不会这样做,让我们关注常数,
我们换种方式。先看看常数
Wouldn't it be kind of cool if I could like, build a table,
岂不是很酷的如果我可以喜欢,建立一个表,
有没有其它更好的方式来实现呢？比如用某种参照表？
Okay, I'll do square brackets to hold my table, And
好吧,我做的方括号握住我的表,和
OK，我用中括号定义表格
in this table, I had, like pi and double dot pi, And then,
在这个表中,我,像π和二阶导数π,然后,
在表格里，我定义 "pi" : Double.pi
maybe I had e's does everyone know what the constant e is,
也许我已经e的大家都知道常数e是什么,
然后，应该还有常数 e，
Mathematic 2,71 one something,
数学71一个东西,
一个无理数，约等于 2.71
We have a nice symbol for
我们有一个很好的象征
Swift 有专门的符号来表示它
that and not quite as nice as Double,pi, But it's called
和不太好双,π,但是它叫
但不像 Double.pi 那么优雅
M under bar E, So, and I put all my constants in a table,
M E在酒吧,所以,我把我所有的常量放在一个表,
它叫 M_E。好了，假设我把需要的常量都放在表格里了
And then here in performOperation,
然后在performOperation中,
然后在 performOperation 方法里
I'll just look up the symbol in that table and
我会查找表和象征
我只需要在表格中查找符号
get the value, Wouldn't that be a lot more extensible for
得到的值,不会,更可扩展
找到对应的值。这是不是更具有可扩展性？
constants? Right, I could add all the constants I want,
常量?
我可以加入任何我想要的常量
I just, one line of code each, That would be a lot better
每一行代码,我就会好很多
一行一个，这肯定会比
than putting extra case this blah blah blah, Okay, so
比把额外的情况下等等,所以
很多很多个 switch 的 case 要好
how can we do that? We need to create a table,
我们该怎么做?
OK，那我们怎样实现呢？首先要创建一个表格
So how do we create a table in Swift?
那么,我们如何在迅速创建一个表吗?
那 Swift 怎么创建一个表格呢？
We use the struct called dictionary, okay? So
我们使用结构体被称为字典,好吗?
Swift 有个结构体，叫 Dictionary（字典）
dictionary is how you create a hash table of things, And so
字典是如何创建一个哈希表的事情,所以
字典是你创建哈希表的方法
I'm gonna create a private var,
我要创建一个私有变量,
我定义一个私有变量
I'm gonna call it, I could call it Constants, but
我要叫它,我可以称它为常数,但是
名字可以叫 Constants
I'm gonna call it operations cuz I'm basically, eventually
我要叫它操作因为我基本上,最终
但我叫它 operations
going to enhance it to work for all of our operations,
要提高我们所有的业务工作,
因为它最终会适用于我们所有的运算
And it's gonna be of type Dictionary, Now Dictionary,
要类型的字典,字典,
类型是 Dictionary
you're gonna see a new feature in Swift right here, It, this,
你会看到斯威夫特中的一个新特性,它,,
你所见到的又一个 Swift 语言的特性
you have this feature in Java, as well, It is a generic type,
你有这个特性在Java中,这是一个泛型类型,
你可能在 Java 中也见过，泛型
So a dictionary, it can be a dictionary that goes from
所以一本字典,它可以从一个字典
字典，可以由几乎任何
almost any kind of key to almost any kind of value,
几乎任何一种几乎任何一种价值的关键,
键值对组成
Okay, the key has to implement a certain protocol,
好的,关键要实现一个特定的协议,
但键必须遵循某个协议
It basically has to be hashable, Okay,
它基本上是hashable,好吧,
它基本上必须是 Hashable，具有哈希性
so as long as it's hashable, then it can be a key and
只要hashable,然后它可以是一个关键
所以只要是具有哈希性，就可以成为键
then the value can be any type, So you specify that,
值可以是任何类型,所以你指定,
值可以是任何类型。所以你需要指定类型
same as in Java, the key type,
在Java中,密钥类型相同,
和 Java 一样，指定键的类型
So I'm gonna have my key be a string like pi or e,
所以我要有我的钥匙是一个字符串像π或e,
And then the value is going to be a double,
然后是一个双重的价值,
like Double,pi here, or _E, okay? And believe it or
像双,π或_E,好吗?
not, I can actually say equals this syntax and
不是,我可以等于这个语法和说
it will create one for me with that step in there, okay? So
它将创建一个与这一步对我来说,好吗?
open square bracket, key colon value comma key colon value,
开放的方括号,键值逗号键结肠值,
that's how you can put a dictionary,
你可以把字典,
Now of course, you can add things to a dictionary and
当然,您可以添加字典和
remove things, and get things out of dictionary,
删除的东西,把事情的字典,
I'll show you that in a second, But
我将向您展示,但是
this is a nice way to do this, So
这是一个不错的方法,所以
let's do that, Okay, so we have this nice dictionary,
做一下,好吧,我们有这个很好的字典,
So now we could use this dictionary of operations and
现在我们可以使用这个字典的操作
performOperation, I'm gonna say,
performOperation中,我会说,
if I can let the constant that I want equal the operation
如果我可以让常数相等操作
that matches that symbol then, now why am I doing if let here
相匹配的象征,现在如果让我做这里的原因
for operations sub-symbol? This operation sub-symbol,
操作次符号?
that's how you look up a symbol in a dictionary, right?
这就是你在字典中查找一个符号,对吧?
Operation to the dictionary, click on it, right?
操作字典,点击它,对吧?
To dictionary, strings and doubles, So you look it up,
字典,字符串和双打,所以你查一下,
When you look it up, it returns an optional of
当你看到它的时候,它返回一个可选的
the value, Why, anyone think why it would do that?
价值,为什么,有人认为它为什么会这么做?
>> It might not be there,
> >这可能不是,
>> Exactly, it might not be in
> >,也许不是
the table, Okay, what if I say operations sub X,
桌上,好吧,如果我说什么操作,
that's gonna return not set, because there's no
会返回没有设置,因为没有
X in this table, Only pi and e are in there, okay? So that's
X在这个表中,只有π和e在那里,好吗?
why I have to do if let there, and if the constant is there,
为什么我要做如果让,如果不变,
now I can set my accumulator equal to that constant,
现在我可以设置蓄电池等于常数,
okay? Because this constant is gonna be a Double, because
好吧?
this is a Dictionary that has Doubles as its values, okay?
这是一本字典,双打作为它的值,对吧?
That's cool, Let's go ahead,
那很酷,让我们继续,
Let's run it, That's all we need to do, So
让我们运行它,这就是我们需要做的,所以
now we've built, for constants only, a much more extensible
现在我们已经建成,为常数,更可扩展的
internal architecture here, to our calculator brain,
内部架构,我们的计算器大脑,
So of course, square root's not gonna work, okay,
当然,平方根不会工作,好吧,
but pi works, and if I add an e button, it would do e, Okay,
但π,如果我添加一个按钮,它会做e,好吧,
everybody cool with what I did there? But
每个人都明白我所做的吗?
of course, that's kind of useless just for constants,
当然,这是一种无用的常数,
We wanna be something like this, watch this, Quote,
我们想要这样的,看这个报价,
do my Emoji & Symbols here,
做我Emoji &符号,
There's our square root, square root colon,
这就是我们的根,根结肠,
what do we wanna put over here? How about square root?
我们想把这里的什么?
Okay, and maybe a cosine, Put cosine there,
好吧,也许一个余弦,余弦,
And wouldn't that be cool if we could do that, okay?
不会,很酷如果我们能这样做,好吗?
Because now we'd really have an extensible table,
因为现在我们真的有一个可扩展的表,
it can do constant and also can do these unary functions,
它可以不变,也可以做这些一元函数,
But we got a problem here, because square root is most
但我们有一个问题,因为最平方根
definitely not a Double, right? Square root
肯定不是一个双,对吗?
is like a function, so that's no good, So we're gonna,
就像一个函数,这是不好,所以我们要,
if we wanna have a dictionary that has mixed things in it,
如果我们想要有一个字典,复杂的东西,
we need to create a type here that represents those
我们需要创建一个代表这些类型
mixed things, So that's what we're gonna do, we're gonna
混合的东西,这就是我们要做的,我们会
create a new type, okay? This is gonna have a data type that
创建一个新类型,好吗?
you're gonna be somewhat used to, to other languages, but
你要多少,其他语言,但是
you're gonna see it much more powerful in Swift,
你会看到它在迅速更强大,
I'm gonna make it a private type that's embedded inside my
我将使它成为一个私人嵌入我的类型
CalculatorBrain, so you can have types within types and
的计算器大脑,所以你可以在类型和类型
it's just a scoping issue, that's just a naming issue,
这只是一个范围的问题,这只是一个命名问题,
okay? The name of this is gonna be CalculatorBrain,
好吧?
the dot, what I call it here, And it's not gonna be a struct
点,我叫它,它不会是一个结构体
or a class, it's gonna be an enum, Does everyone
或一个类,它会是一个枚举,每一个人
know what an enum is in other classes? It's basically a data
知道什么是enum在其他类?
structure that has discrete values, Right,
结构的离散值,
it can only be one, like case this, case that, whatever,
情况下一样,它只能是一个,无论如何,
It can only be one of a discrete value and
它只能被一个离散值和之一
the same thing here in Swift, I'm gonna call it Operation,
同样的事情在斯威夫特,我会叫它操作,
and it's gonna have case constant and
会有常数,
case unaryOperation, So those are the two kinds of things,
unaryOperation,这是两种东西,
And then I'm gonna make this Dictionary return an Operation
然后我把这本字典返回一个操作
instead of a Double, Okay, so that means I have change all
而不是双,好了,这意味着我已经改变
of these, to say Operation,constant, because
可以说,这些操作,常数,因为
this is a constant, We'll just comment that out for a second,
这是一个常数,我们就评论说第二个,
And then this is also an Operation,constant,
这也是一个操作,常数,
This one will be an Operation,unaryOperation,
这将是一个操作,unaryOperation,
I can just call that Operation,unary,
我可以称之为操作,一元,
We'll say unary operation,
我们会说一元运算,
Operation,unaryOperation, okay?
操作,unaryOperation,好吗?
Cool! Okay, we can't do this anymore, of course, cuz now
太酷了!
it's not a constant that we're pulling out of there,
这不是一个常数,我们退出,
It's actually an operation, okay? And obviously,
它实际上是一个操作,好吗?
we can't do that because this constant here,
我们不能这样做,因为这个常数,
is now an operation not a double, So we can't say that
现在手术不是一个双,所以我们不能说
equals that, okay? So this is good, This is getting better,
=,好吗?
We've got our table to be able to have both things, But
我们有我们的桌子能够都东西,但是
in doing this, I've lost the fundamental meaning
在做这个,我已经失去了最根本的意义
of all of these things, I commented it out, So
所有的这些事情,我说出来,所以
now this table is kind of useless, right?
这表是一种无用的,对吧?
It knows that pi is a constant,
它知道π是一个常数,
It knows that square root is a unary operation,
它知道平方根是一元运算,
But it's so what? Because we can't do any of them, And
但那又怎样?
this is where, something you've heard of before,
在这里,你以前听说过的东西,
associated values comes in, Remember optional has
关联值,记得可选
this thing where when it's in the set stage it has this
这个东西当它在设置阶段
associated value that's associated with the set state,
相关值相关的设置状态,
but is not associated with the not set state? Okay, optional
但不是没有设置相关的国家吗?
is an enum, It's an enum with two cases, The not set case,
enum,enum和两个情况下,没有设置的情况下,
which is called none and the set case, which is called sum,
叫做没有设置情况,叫做,
And in the sum case, it has a little associated value with
在的情况下,它有一个小值有关
it, And we can do the exact same thing, okay? In our enum,
它,我们可以做相同的事情,好吗?
when the case is a constant, we can have an associated
情况下是一个常数,我们可以有一个相关的
Double, And that's, we just put it right there and
双,,我们只是把它放在那里
we can actually could have multiple associated values,
我们可以可以有多个相关的值,
We only need one for constants, But we can have
我们只需要一个常数,但我们可以有
this associated value, Okay, so associated values
这个值有关,所以相关的值
are something not specific to optionals, It's for
可选的是不特定的,是吗
all enums in Swift, So this is super powerful because now
所有枚举迅速,这是超级强大的因为现在
when I add a constant into this table, for example,
当我向表添加一个常数,例如,
I can just associate Double,pi with it,
我可以将翻倍,π,
Same thing with this constant, I'll just associate the value
这个常数也是一样,我就把价值
of e with it, Okay, now we'll get to these ones in a second,
e的,好的,现在我们会得到这些的,
A little more complicated there, All right, so
有点复杂,所以
now I've got a table with got constants in there and
现在我有一个表有常数和
I actually know the values,
其实我知道的值,
So down here, when I get the operation out of here, right,
所以在这里,当我得到操作离开这里,对了,
this is a type Operation,
这是一个类型的操作,
it's one of these enums, How do I look at each of these,
这是其中的一个枚举,我怎么看这些,
and like get this associated value? Well, how would you
就像这个关联值吗?
look at the values of an enum in another language?
看一个枚举的值在另一种语言?
You would probably switch on them, So
你可能会打开他们
I'm gonna switch on this operation and
我要打开这个操作
I'm gonna do a case for when it's a constant, And
我要做的,当它是一个常数,和
I'm gonna do a case, we'll do colon and break,
我要做一个情况下,我们会做结肠和休息,
And I'm gonna do a case for when it's a unaryOperation,
,我要做一个案例的时候unaryOperation,
and break on that case, okay? And I don't even have to
,在这种情况下,好吗?
say default here, because these are the only two values
说违约,因为这是唯一的两个值
that an operation can be, cuz it's an enum,
可以将一个操作,因为这是一个枚举,
it only has one of these two values, Now here, you can see,
现在只有这两个值之一,在这里,你可以看到,
it already put this in parentheses right here,
它已经把这里的括号内,
Okay, it wants to help you get that associated value out,
好的,希望帮助你得到相关的价值,
Okay, awesome, how do we do that?
好的,太棒了,我们怎么做呢?
We say let associatedConstantValue or
我们说让associatedConstantValue或
whatever we wanna call this variable, And
不管我们想叫这个变量
that means inside here, associatedConstantValue
这意味着在这里面,associatedConstantValue
is gonna be that associated value, Now we would never call
会关联值,现在我们不会叫
it associatedConstantValue, We'll rename it in a second,
associatedConstantValue,我们将重命名,
But now what are we gonna do with it? Well,
但是现在我们要用它做什么?
in the constant case we're just gonna set our accumulator
在恒定的情况下我们要组蓄电池
to that associated value, Now, why we wouldn't call this
关联值,为什么我们不叫它
associatedConstantValue? Well, first of all, anyone reading
associatedConstantValue吗?
this code knows that this is the associated value,
这段代码知道这是相关的值,
so you don't need to say associated, And we know i's
所以你不需要说相关联,我们知道我的
a constant because we're in the constant case, so
一个常数,因为我们在恒定的情况下,
i's really a waste to say that,
我真的是一个浪费,
So, we would just say value here, Cuz that's what it is,
所以,我们只会说值,因为这是它是什么,
i's the constant value that's associated with it, okay?
我的与之相关的常量值,好吗?
We don't need break, Everybody got that?
我们不需要休息,大家都明白了吗?
By the way, switches are slightly different in Swift in
顺便说一下,开关迅速的略有不同
that they don't fall into each other, When you have constant,
他们不属于彼此,当你有常数,
it does this, and it's done, It doesn't go down, fall down
它,它,它不下去,倒了
to the next case, okay? So you don't need break at the end
接下来的情况,好吗?
of every single one, which is really nice, All right?
每一个人,这是非常好的,对吧?
So this is great, So should this work? I think so,
这是伟大的,所以这应该工作吗?
Let's try it, All right,
让我们试试,好吧,
So, Pi, okay, square root we haven't done anything with,
π,好的,根我们什么都没做,
but pi should work, Let's try, Bingo, okay,
但π应该工作,让我们试试,宾果,好吧,
So you see how pi is working here?
所以你看看π是在这里工作吗?
We're saying to look up pi in this table, It finds that
我们说在这个表查找π,它发现
it's a constant operation with this as the associated value,
它是一个常数操作与这相关的值,
We switch on that operation, Find out that it's a constant,
我们开关操作,发现它是一个常数,
We let value equal the associated value,
我们让价值平等相关的价值,
and then we just set that to the accumulator,
然后我们组蓄电池,
And now that's our result, the next time they ask for result
现在这是我们的结果,下次他们要求的结果
that's what we got, Okay, now let's do unary operation,
这就是我们,好吧,现在让我们做一元运算,
Okay, this one's a little tougher, okay?
好吧,这个有点困难,好吗?
Cuz really what I wanna do is this, Right?
因为我真正想做的是这个,对吗?
The associated value wants to be those functions,
想要这些功能相关的价值,
Can I do that in Swift? Of course!
我可以用快速吗?
We wouldn't be here if we couldn't do that,
我们不会在这里,如果我们做不到,
How do we make an associated value be a function?
如何让一个关联的值是一个函数?
Well the cool thing about Swift is that functions
斯威夫特是最酷的功能
are normal types, Just like a double, any struct,
是正常的类型,就像一个翻倍,任何结构,
a class, no difference between that and a double,
一个类,没有区别,双,
So how do I go back up to my enum, and it have
所以我怎么回到我的枚举,并且它
an associated type here be a double? How do I say,
一个关联的类型是双吗?
the type which is a function that takes a double and
类型是一个函数,接受一个和的两倍
returns a double? Cuz that's what I want in here,
返回一个双人床?
This is a unary operation, so
这是一个一元运算,所以
I need this to be a function that takes a double and
我需要这是一个函数,接受一个和的两倍
returns a double, We just type it, function that takes
返回一个双,我们只是类型,函数
a double, returns a double, Just type it right in there,
双,返回一个双类型它就在那里,
This is a type, Just a type, just like string,
这是一个类型,类型,就像字符串,
but it happens to be a function, Now I'm
但它是一个函数,我现在
going to take a time-out right here just to show you a little
将暂停在这里给你一点
bit more about this function types,
更多关于这个函数类型,
to make sure you're getting this, And what I'm gonna do is
确保你得到这个,我要做的是什么
I'm gonna create a new thing called a playground,
我要创建一个名为一个操场的新事物,
So a playground is just a place we can play around with
操场就是我们可以玩耍的地方
iOS code, Okay? So you just say new playground,
iOS代码,好吗?
this is gonna be an iOS playground, I'm gonna call it
这将是一个iOS操场,我会叫它
my CalculatorPlayground, I can call it anything I want,
CalculatorPlayground,我可以称之为任何我想要的,
Just gonna save it on disk so that what I
要将其保存在磁盘上,以便我
type in here when I'm playing gets saved for the next time,
类型在这里当我玩会保存在接下来的时间,
You can put it anywhere you want,
你可以放任何你想要的,
I recommend the same place, home directory, Developer,
我建议同一个地方,主目录,开发人员,
Okay, don't put it inside another project or whatever,
好了,不要把它在另一个项目,
And you can see the playground looks like this, On the left,
你可以看到操场上是这样,在左边,
you can type any iOS code you want, And on the right,
你可以输入任何你想要的iOS的代码,在右边,
it's going to evaluate what's on the left and show you not
左边的评估是什么,让你没有
only, well, it's basically gonna show you the result or
,它基本上是要给你或结果
the value of any var that it finds,
它发现的任何var的价值,
So here it found this var string, str, and it's
这发现这var字符串,str,
showing you the value of str over here, Okay? So I can say,
显示你的价值str在这里,好吗?
for example, let i = 27 and it's gonna say that 27 is what
例如,让我= 27岁,会说,27是什么
it sees there, But I'm gonna create a new var,
它看到,但我要创建一个新的变量,
I'm gonna call it f, Its type is gonna be a function that
我要叫它f,其类型是一个函数
takes a double and returns a double, Okay, that's its type,
双并返回一个双,好吧,这是它的类型,
I could have said f, var f string, but
我可能说f,f var字符串,但是
I said it's a function that takes a double and
我说这是一个函数,它接受一个和的两倍
returns a double, And I'm gonna set the value of f,
返回一个双,我设置的值,
I'm gonna set it equal to square root, Okay,
我要把它等于平方根,好吧,
I mean it's a function that takes a double and
我的意思是这是一个函数,它接受一个和的两倍
returns a double, So I can say f = square root, Now how do I
返回一个双,所以我可以说f =平方根,现在我如何
actually call this function? Well I'm gonna let x equal f
调用这个函数呢?
of 81, for example, Okay, so I call this variable,
81年,例如,好的,所以我把这个变量,
right here, which is a double that takes a double,
在这里,这是一个增加一倍,两倍
just like it was a function, And if I were to go back and
就像它是一个函数,如果我回去
change this to cosine, look what happens, Okay,
改变这个余弦,看看发生了什么,好了,
so now f is cosine so now I'm getting the cosine of 81,
所以现在f是余弦现在我得到81年的余弦,
I can even write my own function,
我甚至可以编写自己的函数,
how bout func changeSign,
怎么样func changeSign,
let's say it takes a double and
假设需要一和
returns a double, okay, So it's a regular function,
返回一个双,好吧,这是一个常规的函数,
returns the changeSigned operand, right,
返回changeSigned操作数,
operand changed sign, So now I could go down here and
操作数改变符号,所以现在我可以在这里
change this to be changeSign, function I wrote, And
改变这种changeSign,我写的函数,
now I'm getting minus 81, Okay? So everyone's seeing how
现在我得到- 81,好吗?
this type functions as a type? They're just normal type,
这种类型的功能作为一个类型?
Absolutely, you can use a function as a type anywhere
当然,你可以在任何地方使用函数作为类型
you can use any other type, Argument to a method,
您可以使用任何其他类型,论证方法,
associated value in an enum, local variable, anything,
关联值的枚举,局部变量,任何东西,
No restriction on it, okay? I'm even gonna take the,
不限制它,好吗?
note also, by the way, the change sign has an external
还请注意,顺便说一下,改变了外部迹象
name, operand, When you tall, call change sign,
名称、操作数高时,调用改变符号,
looks like this, See? We've got this operand, It's okay,
就像这样,看到了吗?
when I call it down here, I don't have to say f(operand),
当我叫它下面,我不必说f(操作数),
In fact, I can't say that, And that's because f
事实上,我不能说,因为f
is just a function that takes a double, returns a double,
只是一个函数,它接受一个翻倍,返回一个双,
It can be any function that takes a double and
它可以是任何需要双和函数
returns a double, so you can't have those external names in
返回一个双,所以你不能有外部的名字
there, cuz it can be any function,
因为它可以是任何函数,
As you change it you can't be changing this, so, anyway,
当你改变你不能改变,所以,无论如何,
just a minor note there, So I'm gonna take changeSign,
只是一个小的注意,所以我要把changeSign,
actually, and copy and paste it back into my code up here,
事实上,复制粘贴回我的代码,
so I just made a new function, it's even a nice global
所以我就做了一个新功能,甚至全球
to this file, function called changeSign, And
这个文件,函数称为changeSign,
I can go back here and say, changeSign, let's do something
我可以回到这里,changeSign,让我们做点什么
for changeSign, I think I can remember how to do this,
changeSign,我想我能记得如何做到这一点,
there, Ctrl + C, Cmd + Ctrl + Space, something like that,
那里,Ctrl + C Cmd + Ctrl + Space,,
let's go here, Edit, Okay, we need something for
我们去这里,编辑好了,我们需要一些
changeSign, I think I have one here, this one, okay?
changeSign,我认为我有一个在这里,这个,好吗?
It's not really change sign [LAUGH] but,
这不是(笑),但真正改变标志,
it's all right we'll use it for that, And, so
没关系,我们将使用它,因此
this is an operation, an Operation,unaryOperation(chan-
这是一个操作,一个操作,unaryOperation(chan -
geSign), Okay? Perfectly legal, Okay, everybody got
geSign),好吗?
that? So now, down here in our switch, in the same
了吗?
way that we grabbed the constant value with let value,
我们抓住了让值的恒定值,
let's grab that associated function with let function,
让我们抓住相关函数与函数,
And again we can call, this doesn't have to be a function,
我们可以打电话,这不必是一个函数,
This could be f, It could be func, Can't be func, because
这可能是f,可以是函数,不能函数,因为
that's a keyword, but function it could be, Okay? So we got
这是一个关键字,但可以是函数,对吧?
this unary operation, What are we gonna do? Well we just want
这个一元运算,我们要做什么?
to call this thing with the accumulator, Okay?
与蓄电池叫这个东西,好吗?
But of course we'd better, I'm sorry, we want our accumulator
当然我们最好,对不起,我们希望我们的蓄电池
to equal, calling that function with the accumulator,
与蓄电池相同的情况下,调用这个函数,
We'd better check though to make sure this is not nil, So
我们最好检查一下,确保这不是零,所以
I'm actually gonna do something a little different,
我要做点不同,
Instead of if let, I'm gonna say if the accumulator does
相反,如果让我会说如果蓄电池
not equal nil, Then we'll do this, This is another
不等于零,那么我们会这样做,这是另一个
way to protect against this crashing your app, Okay,
方法来防止这个应用程序崩溃,好吧,
somewhat similar to if let operand equal accumulator,
有点类似于如果让操作数等于蓄电池,
but I'm just actually checking to see if accumulator is in
但实际上我只是检查蓄电池
the not set state,
没有设置状态,
accumulator isn't optional, so it can be equal to nil or
蓄电池不是可选的,所以它可以等于零
it's equal to something else, and it has an associated value
它等于别的东西,它都有一个关联的值
like these things, All right? That's all we need to do,
像这样的事情,对吧?
Let's take a look, Whoops, we, we have errors there?
让我们看一看,哎呀,我们我们有错误吗?
No, we don't, Okay, All right,
不,我们没有,好吧,好吧,
So, pi, still good, 81, square root,
π,还好,81年,平方根,
Working like a charm, Okay, and again if we add cosine and
工作就像一个魅力,好的,如果我们添加cos和
those which we are going to add those in a second, but for
那些我们要添加的,但是
time I'm not adding them in, But we'll add cosine and
时间我不加入他们,但我们将添加余弦和
all, actually I'm, forget it, let's do it,
实际上我,算了吧,让我们做它,
Let's go back to our UI right here and let's add those other
让我们回到我们的UI在这里添加其他
buttons, Let's put cosine in here, Cosine,
按钮,在这里我们把cos,余弦,
and let's even put our little change sign that we did there,
甚至让我们把我们的小变化表明我们做,
Ctrl+Cmd+Space, there we go, Change sign,
Ctrl + Cmd +空间,好了,改变符号,
Put the change sign in there, So we'll put those in there
把改变符号,所以我们把这些
and that's all we need to do in my UI,
这是我们要做的在我的用户界面,
It can just run again, because my brain,
它可以再次运行,因为我的大脑,
my model already knows how to do those operations,
我的模型已经知道如何做这些操作,
So I can put any operation my brain knows how to do
所以我可以把我的大脑知道如何做任何操作
into my calculator's UI and it'll just work,
进我的计算器的UI,它会工作,
So here we got, you know, how about pi cosine, -1,0,
我们,你知道,如何πcos,1,0,
all right? Change sign, positive 1,0, All right, so
好吧?
this is really looking nice, because our calculator brain,
这真的是看起来不错,因为我们的计算器大脑,
still hardly any code in here, and yet
仍然在这里几乎没有任何代码,然而
now it's fully extensible for both constants and
现在是完全可扩展的常量和
unary operations, What's next? Binary operations,
一元操作,接下来是什么?
5 times 3 equals, okay, much more difficult, right?
5乘以3 =,更加困难,对吧?
Because there's actually two operations there when we do 5
因为有两个操作当我们做5
times 3 equals, There's the times, which puts you in this
* 3 =,《纽约时报》,让你在这
weird pending state, and then there's the equals which
奇怪的挂起状态,还有的=
actually finishes the 5 times 3 equals, right? So I'm
实际完成5乘以3 = ?
gonna need some data structure to remember the 5 times
需要一些数据结构记住5次
until the equals comes along, Okay, so let's do that,
直到等于出现,好吧,让我们来做,
let's add a data structure for that, Actually, before we even
让我们添加一个数据结构,实际上,之前
do that, let's back up here and talk about all this mess,
这样做,让我们回到这里,谈论这一切混乱,
What's this gonna be like for binary operations? So we need
这是什么会喜欢为二进制操作吗?
a binary operation here, And what's its type gonna be?
一个二元运算,其类型会是什么?
What's its associated value gonna be? What do you think?
它的关联值会是什么?
How about a function that takes two double and
一个函数,它接受两个双和怎么样
returns a double? All right, and we're also gonna need
返回一个双人床?
an equals operation as well, And so
一个等于操作,所以
we can just go down here and do, for example, times,
我们可以去做,例如,时间,
let's do times, Oops, space, there we go,
让我们做次,哦,空间,好了,
I've got a nice mathematical times symbol here, Okay,
我有一个很好的数学时代象征,好吧,
we have to enter in Operation,binaryOperation, And
我们必须输入操作,binaryOperation,
we need multiply basically here, So I'm gonna make my own
我们需要乘基本上在这里,所以我要做我自己
multiply function, We'll just put multiply there,
乘法函数,我们将把用在那里,
Also of course, I need equals which is Operation,equals,
当然,我需要等于操作,等于,
Okay, put those on my table, So this multiply,
好吧,把这些放在我的桌子,这成倍增加,
where's that? There's no function called multiply,
它在哪里?
Well, just like I did changeSign up here,
嗯,就像我做changeSign,
I'm gonna create my own little func,
我要创造我自己的小函数,
multiply, It's gonna take op1, which is a Double,
用,它会采取op1,双,
and op2, which is a Double, And
和《凤凰社》第2章,这是双重的,
it's gonna return a Double, of course, Oops, and
当然,它会返回一个双哦,
it's just gonna return op1 times op2, okay?
只是要返回op1倍op2,好吗?
So I got this nice function up here, Fits in here nice,
所以我有一个漂亮的函数,适合在这里好,
no error, everything's fine there, got that, So
没有错误,一切都很好,明白了,所以
now we have the hard part of what do we do with the case
现在我们有努力的一部分,我们该怎么做
here that is binary operation? We still have a function,
这里是二元运算?
but now it's a function that takes two doubles and returns
但是现在它是一个函数,它接受两个双打和回报
a double, All right, so what are we gonna do here? Get,
双,好吧,那么我们要做什么呢?
like I said, we're gonna need some kind of data structure
就像我说的,我们需要某种类型的数据结构
to remember five times and
记住,5倍
wait till we get another case which is equals, okay?
等到我们得到另一个例子就是等于,好吗?
And we're gonna have to do something in here, So
我们要做一些在这里,
let's take a time out here and create another data structure
让我们来一次这里创建另一个数据结构
to remember five times while we're waiting for
记得当我们等待5倍
three equals to happen, So I'm gonna make it a struct,
3 =发生,所以我要使它成为一个结构体,
It's also gonna be an embedded private struct, just like this
也会嵌入式私人结构,就像这样
was embedded private enum, So the name of this enum,
嵌入式私人枚举,所以这个枚举的名字,
its full name is CalculatorBrain,Operation, but
它的全名是计算器大脑操作,但是
as long as I'm using it inside this struct,
只要我使用它在这个结构体,
we can just call it operation, like we did right here,
我们可以叫它操作,像我们一样,
Okay, so same thing here,
这里也一样,
I'm gonna call this one PendingBinaryOperation,
我要叫这个PendingBinaryOperation,
Okay, it's gonna be a PendingBinaryOperation,
好吧,它会成为一个PendingBinaryOperation,
And it's gonna have two vars, One is the function which is
会有两个var,一个是函数
gonna be, it takes two Doubles, returns a Double, And
会,需要两个双打,返回一个双,
it's going to have the first operand, which is a Double,
它将第一个操作数,这是一个翻倍,
So it's just gonna be a struct that holds those two things,
所以它只是将一个结构体,拥有这两件事,
Now never forget that structs in Swift can have methods and
现在永远不会忘记,在迅速可以有方法和结构
things like that, In fact,
事实上,类似这样的事情
I'm gonna put a method on here just to remind us of that,
我将一个方法在这里只是提醒我们,
I'm gonna have a func called perform which will
我要有一个函数调用执行
perform this binary operation, Now what does
执行这个二元运算,现在什么
it need to perform it? It needs a second operand,
它需要执行吗?
Okay? And it's gonna return a double, Okay,
好吧?
now, notice the naming here, Why did I use this naming,
现在,请注意这里的命名,为什么我使用这个命名,
with as my external and here secondOperand as my internal?
与我这里secondOperand作为内部和外部?
Well, secondOperand is the internal,
嗯,secondOperand内部,
because that's what this argument is,
因为这是这个论点是什么,
And in my code here, I want the firstOperand and
在我的代码,我想firstOperand和
secondOperand to have the right names, But
secondOperand正确的名字,但是
I'm using with because when someone calls this, they're
我使用,因为当有人叫这个,他们
gonna say perform(with: 5,0), And of course,
会说执行(0):5日,当然,
if they're performing a pending binary operation, so
如果他们执行一个悬而未决的二元运算,所以
this makes perfect sense, If you say binary operation,
这非常有意义,如果你说二元运算,
perform(with: 5,0), It makes sense, right? And these
执行(0):5日,它是有意义的,对吧?
internal names, even though they're only used internally,
内部的名字,即使他们只在内部使用,
you can think of them as part of the documentation,
你可以把它们作为文档的一部分,
Cuz anyone who sees the documentation of this method,
因为人看到这种方法的文档,
he's gonna see both with and secondOperand, see? So they're
他会看到secondOperand,看到了吗?
kind of getting a little bit of documentation that that
的有点的文档
with is with the secondOperand to this binary operation,
与是secondOperand二元运算,
Okay, and how would we perform this? Well, we would just
好吧,这和我们如何执行?
return the firstOperand times the secondOperand, okay? But
返回firstOperand乘以secondOperand,好吗?
we're not doing times here, we're doing this function,
我们这里不做次,我们做这个函数,
So I'm gonna call it that function with the firstOperand
所以我要叫它与firstOperand这个函数
and the secondOperand, Okay, this is a really simple little
secondOperand,好吧,这是一个很简单的小
method, but I just wanted to make it clear,
方法,但我只是想弄清楚,
Notice this method doesn't have mutating on it, Because
注意这种方法没有变异,因为
it doesn't actually change the PendingBinaryOperation,
它实际上并不改变PendingBinaryOperation,
right? It just returns to the evaluation of the function,
对吧?
but it doesn't change any internal values, Also notice,
但它也不会改变任何内部值,注意,
these are lets, That's because I'm gonna create this
这些是允许,那是因为我要创建这个
PendingBinaryOperation in a moment with these two things
与这两个东西PendingBinaryOperation一会儿
set and I'm never gonna change them,
设置和我永远不会改变,
So they are constants in this struct, Now, also notice,
所以他们是常数在这个结构体,现在,也注意到,
no error that says you don't have an initializer and you
没有错误,你不有一个初始化程序和你说
have these two uninitialized vars, Again, this is a struct,
有这两个未初始化的var,再一次,这是一个结构体,
Structs automatically get a free initializer
结构自动获得一个免费的初始值设定项
which will initialize all of these things, And
将初始化所有的这些东西,
in fact, let's use that right now,
事实上,我们使用,现在,
I'm gonna create a private var, which I'm gonna call pbo,
我要创建一个私有变量,我会叫pbo,
PendingBinaryOperation, but only temporarily, because
PendingBinaryOperation,但这只是暂时的,因为
this is a bad name, I'm mostly doing it so things won't
这是一个坏名声,我主要做所以事情不会
wrap, cuz I'm using a big font so you can see here, I'm gonna
包装,因为我用大字体,所以你可以看到,我要
go actually change this back to a better name in a second,
实际上改变这一切回到一个更好的名字,
But this pbo is a PendingBinaryOperation,
但这pbo PendingBinaryOperation,
and optional,
和可选的,
Why is this an optional PendingBinaryOperation?
为什么这是一个可选的PendingBinaryOperation吗?
Cuz we're not always in the middle of a binaryOperation,
因为我们不是binaryOperation总是在中间,
Only when the person taps five times, Okay,
只有当人利用五次,好吧,
if we'd said five square root,
如果我们说5根,
we're not in the middle of a PendingBinaryOperation, so
我们不是在中间PendingBinaryOperation,如此
this has to be not set, Are you starting to get a feel for
这是没有设置,你开始了解
how we use optionals all over the place,
我们如何使用可选的地方,
to be semantically exactly what we mean? And here,
语义上正是我们的意思吗?
if we're not in the middle of PendingBinaryOperation,
如果我们不是PendingBinaryOperation中间,
this is not set, So it's an optional, All right, so
这不是,这是一个可选的,所以
when you've pressed the times,
当你按下时间,
5 times, all I'm gonna do here is remember, or create,
5倍,所有我要做的就是记住,或创建,
a PendingBinaryOperation,
PendingBinaryOperation,
So I'm gonna say pbo = PendingBinaryOperation,
所以我想说pbo = PendingBinaryOperation,
Now when I tab here, and I do the open parentheses, Look,
现在当我标签,我开括号,看,
it's showing me that there's already an initializer,
告诉我,已经有一个初始化,
one that, tab, takes function and firstOperand,
选项卡,需要功能和firstOperand,
Woo-hoo! So this is that free initializer I get,
啊!
because I'm a struct down here, not a class, So what is
因为我是一个结构体,不是一个类,那么
the function? Well, that's just this function right here,
这个函数呢?
that we got as our associated value,
我们作为我们的相关值,
That's the function in the binaryOperation,
binaryOperation的函数,
And what's the firstOperand?
和firstOperand是什么?
Well, it's our current accumulator, right,
这是我们当前的蓄电池,
five times are equal if it's a five, okay? Now,
五次都是平等的,如果这是一个五,好吗?
here I'm unwrapping it, so I better do if accumulator
我打开它,所以我最好如果蓄电池
does not equal nil, Cuz I don't want to crash here and
不等于零,因为我不想和崩溃吗
I'm, so that means I'm gonna ignore times, If you've
我,这意味着我要忽略,如果你
pressed times and you haven't given me an operand,
按次,你没有给我一个操作数,
we're just gonna ignore that, It's like if you start up your
我们会忽略,就像如果你启动
calculator and say, times 3 equals, I'm gonna ignore it,
计算器,乘以3等于,我要忽略它,
because I don't have any operands who times it by,
因为我没有通过任何操作数倍,
Okay, so that's good, that's what I want, Also, when I
好吧,这很好,这就是我想要的,而且,当我
have this times, I'm gonna set my accumulator here to nil,
有一次,我要我的累加器设置为零,
Because I'm in this weird half state five times,
因为我在这个奇怪的一半国家的5倍,
my accumulator is waiting for
我的蓄电池是等待
the three equals to be set to anything,
三个等于被设置为任何东西,
So I'm setting it to nil not set for the moment, All right,
所以我将它设置为零没有设置目前,好吧,
so that's it, that's all I need to do when times is hit,
就是这样,这就是我需要做的时候,
But now when equals is hit, I have the the three, and
但是现在等于击中时,我有三个
I need to calculate five times three,
我需要计算3、5倍
So I need to actually call this perform down here, So
所以我需要真正称之为执行下面,所以
I'm gonna put this in its own little method, I'm gonna call
我要把它放到自己的小方法,我要打电话
it performBinaryOperation, actually, we'll even say
实际上,我们甚至会说,这performBinaryOperation
performPendingBinary, oops, BinaryOperation, okay,
BinaryOperation performPendingBinary,哎呀,好吧,
I'm putting it in another method,
我把它在另一个方法,
you'll see why in a moment, Okay, so I'm gonna do private
你就会明白为什么,所以我要做私人的
func which is that, now what am I gonna do in here? Well,
函数就是,现在我要在这里做什么呢?
here I'm going to perform that pendingBinaryOperation, So
这里我要执行pendingBinaryOperation,所以
I'm gonna do pbo,perform, and what am I gonna perform with?
我要做pbo、执行和我要做什么?
I'm gonna perform with the current accumulator, okay?
我要执行与当前蓄电池,好吗?
Now notice this put a question mark right there, okay?
现在注意到这把一个问号,好吗?
The reason I need a question mark there, really,
我需要一个问号,真的,
what I wanted was exclamation point, Because pbo, here,
我想要的是感叹号,因为pbo,这里,
is an optional, and I need to unwrap it,
是一个可选的,我需要打开它,
But what's really cool is if instead of exclamation point,
但是真正酷的是如果不是感叹号,
you put question mark, then it will unwrap it, but
你把问号,那么它将打开它,但是
it's not set, it will just ignore this line,
它不是,它只会忽略这条线,
Ignore the rest of the line, okay? So
忽略其余的线?
that's kind of a cool feature, But I'm not gonna do that,
这是一个很酷的功能,但我不会这样做,
cuz I didn't really talked enough about it, so
因为我没有足够的谈论它,所以
I'm gonna unwrap it, So here I need to make sure pbo is not
我要打开它,所以在这里我需要确保pbo不是
nil, And I need to make sure that the accumulator is also
零,我需要确保蓄电池也
not nil, okay? So if those two things aren't true,
不是零,好吗?
I don't really want to be
我不真的想要
doing this line of code right here,
做这行代码,
right? So I'm performing it, I get the results and
对吧?
I'm going to put that in my accumulator, okay?
我要把我的蓄电池,好吗?
So my accumulator is no longer nil, why is this happening?
所以我的蓄电池不再是零,为什么会这样?
It's the third time, mutating, all right, excellent,
这是第三次,变异,好,很好,
I love it when people catch on real quick, So, yeah, that
我爱它当人们明白真正的快,所以,是的,这
needs to be mutating, cuz this is changing the accumulator,
需要变异,因为这是改变蓄电池,
So it's modifying the internal state of the calculator brain,
这是修改计算器大脑的内部状态,
Now, the other thing is no longer am I in the middle
现在,不再另一件事是我在中间
of a pendingBinaryOperation, so I have to set that to nil,
pendingBinaryOperation,所以我必须设置为零,
Okay, cuz I wanna be consistent in all my
好吧,因为我想在我保持一致
code that when that's nil, I'm not in the middle of a pending
零的代码时,我不是在中间的等待
operation, I just had the three equals, okay,
操作,我只有三个=,好吧,
everybody set? Now, I told you I didn't like pbo as a name,
每个人都准备好了吗?
It's a bad name, okay? Someone looking at it would have to go
这是一个糟糕的名字,好吗?
look at the declaration to figure out it,
看《宣言》指出,
A better name here would be pendingBinaryOperation, so
一个更好的名字就是pendingBinaryOperation,所以
I'm gonna change it to that, And here's how you can change
我要改变它,这是如何变化的
the name of something all throughout the context
所有的东西在整个上下文的名称
that it's in, You just mouse over it,
的,你只是鼠标,
I haven't clicked on it, I moused over it,
我没有点击它,我滑过去,
You see that little arrow that appears? If you click on that
你看到那个小箭头出现?
you get a menu and you can say, Edit All in Scope, And
你得到一个菜单,你可以说,编辑都在范围和
now when you change this, it's changing it everywhere, Okay,
现在当你改变,改变它,好吧,
so I changed it from pbo to PendingBinaryOperation,
所以我改变了它从pbo PendingBinaryOperation,
You can see why I did that, because I didn't want
你可以看到我为什么这么做,因为我不想
the wrapping to happen when we were first doing it, okay?
包装发生当我们第一次做,好吗?
So that's it, that's all we need to do for
就是这样,这就是我们要做的
our little Pending BinaryOperation, so
我们的小等待BinaryOperation,所以
let's go ahead and add some pending, some binary, so let'a
让我们添加一些等待,一些二进制,萨那
add some binary operations to our UI, In fact, I'm going
添加一些二进制操作我们的UI,事实上,我走了
to add a few that we don't even have in our table yet,
添加一些我们没有在我们的表,
So let's do times, come up in the space,
让我们来做次,出现在空间,
Yeah, so here's times, but I'm also going to do the other
是的,这是次,但我也要做
ones here divide and plus and it's just so we don't have to
分而加上的,只是我们没有
come back here again to do that, So there's divide, and
再次回到这里,所以有分歧
that there, I'll do another one, do plus and
有,我会做另一个,加和
minus here, So I'm doing command control space,
-在这里,所以我在做命令控制空间,
I guess, to get this little emojis and
我想,这个小emojis和
symbols thing and a plus, okay?
符号的事情和a +,好吗?
And we need one other thing, equals, gotta have an equals
我们需要另一件事,等于,要有一个平等的
button, So we'll put that down there, okay? So now we only
按钮,我们会把它放下,好吗?
have times, so times is the only one that should work but
有次,所以时间是唯一一个但应该工作吗
let's see, Actually I'm gonna bring back that code so
看一下,其实我要带回代码
you can see it at the same time, It's hard to see it all
你可以看到它在同一时间,很难看到这一切
at once, but, All right here we go, okay?
一次,但是,好了好了,好吗?
4 square root, that's still working, pi, still working,
4的平方根,这仍然是工作,π,仍然工作,
How about 8 times 6 equals, wahoo, square root?
8 * 6 =怎么样,火树平方根吗?
Nice, okay, so times is working there beautifully,
好,好,乘以正在那里漂亮,
Now the only thing is, we have to do divide and
现在唯一的问题是,我们必须分而做
all that, so I guess what I have to do is,
这一切,所以我想我要做的是什么,
I go create this four times, And I'm gonna have to go
我去创建这个四次,我得走了
here again and Ctrl+Space again, we'll do divide, And
这里又再次Ctrl + Space,我们会分裂
we'll go here and Ctrl+Space and we'll do plus, And
我们就去这里,Ctrl + Space,我们会加上,和
then we're gonna go here and we'll do command, space, and
然后我们会去这里,我们会做指挥,空间,
we'll do minus, okay? Now, am I gonna have to write,
我们会做-,好吗?
write a method divide and go up here and
写一个方法分而在这里
copy and paste this and do one with divide? You know,
复制和粘贴这有分歧吗?
if I have to do that, all of a sudden, I'm feeling like,
如果我必须这样做,突然间,我感觉,
this whole table business really didn't buy me that
整个表业务真的不给我买
much, right? Cuz I'm still having to create a method for
多,对吧?
every single binary operation I want to do? I mean, for
每一个二进制操作我想做什么?
unary operations it was nice because I had all these built
一元操作很不错,因为我有这些了
in ones, I did have to make this one method, Yeah, I can
的,我有这个方法,是的,我能
even see with unary operations I wanna create a bunch more
即使看到一元操作我想创建一个群
and I'm having to create these other functions,
我需要创建这些其他功能,
It's not really working out for me,
这对我来说并不是真正的工作,
Okay, so how are we gonna fix this? Well, we're gonna use
好的,那么我们要如何解决这个问题?
a feature in Swift, which is really powerful,
迅速的特征,这是强大的,
And you're gonna have to get used to it,
你必须要去适应它,
cuz it's not in a lot of other languages,
因为这不是在很多其他语言,
It is in some other languages,
这是在其他语言中,
I don't wanna make it sound like it's not around,
我不想让它听起来像它不是,
it's definitely around, But may not be something you've
这是肯定,但可能不是你的东西
used in any languages you've used and it's called closures,
用在任何语言你使用,它叫做闭包,
Okay, how many people know what a closure is,
好的,有多少人知道什么是一个闭包,
have heard that before?
以前听说过吗?
See, almost none of you, so a closure is a function
你看,几乎没有,所以一个闭包是一个函数
embedded right in line of your code, okay? And so,
嵌入在代码行,好吗?
we can actually take multiply right here, select its code,
我们可以把用在这里,选择它的代码,
I'm gonna cut it, go down here to where I used it and
我会把它,去这里,我用它
paste it in there, Now if didn't quite work,
粘贴在这里,如果没有工作,
there's two things we need to do, One, this open curly brace
我们需要做两件事,一,这花括号
needs to be at the beginning, So, we're going to
需要在一开始,所以,我们要
replace this open curly brace with the keyword in, and
这花括号替换关键字,和
put the curly brace at the beginning, So
初把花括号
that's how you take a function and put it right in line,
这就是你把一个函数是正确的,
Just literally copy and paste to write in there,
只是随便复制粘贴来写,
Change the curly brace to in and move it to the beginning,
改变花括号,并将它移动到开始,
okay, got that? So now we don't even need multiply,
好吧,明白了吗?
all gone, Now this doesn't look much better,
都走了,现在看起来不更好,
It's still a lot of typing stuff in, but
它仍然是很多类型的东西,但是
let's use Swift's inference of type to make this a lot nicer,
让我们用斯威夫特的推理类型的让这个好很多,
Swift knows that this, right here is this,
迅速知道这,就是这个,
the associated value of that type, So it knows that this
相关的值的类型,所以它知道这个
down here is a function that takes two doubles and
下面是一个函数,它接受两个双打和
returns a double, So we don't need these types right here,
返回一个的两倍,所以我们不需要这些,
get rid of those, Okay,
摆脱那些,好吧,
now it's starting to look better, In fact,
现在开始更好看,事实上,
maybe if I go here and put some things on the same line,
如果我去这里,把一些事情在同一行,
Yeah, now I'm liking it, okay, But we can do even better than
是的,现在我喜欢它,但我们可以做得更好
this, Swift also knows that this returns something,
斯威夫特也知道这回报,这
So we don't overturn, okay, Swift also will let you have
所以我们不推翻,斯威夫特也将给你
any number of arguments you want, Called $0, $1, $2 $3,
你想要的任意数量的参数,名为$ 0 $ 1,$ 2 $ 3,
for however how many, So I don't need that or that,
然而有多少,所以我不需要,或者,
I can say $0 times $1,
我可以说0 * 1美元,
Okay, now I'm winning, Now,
好的,现在我赢了,现在,
the essentials of what is going on here is right there,
这是怎么回事的要点是,
And there's no extraneous types and
没有多余的类型和
all that business, And of course, that means for
所有的业务,当然,这意味着
these other cases like divide, I can say divide,
这些其他情况下像分裂,我可以说,
And for add, here I can see plus, and for subtract,
添加,在这里我可以看到加,减,
I can do minus, even for our friend change sign right here,
我可以做-,甚至对我们的朋友改变符号,
Okay, we can take this copy it paste,
好了,我们可以把这个复制粘贴,
get rid of all this junk because this is just -$0,
摆脱所有这些垃圾,因为这是- 0美元
okay? So, this closures allow you to do this thing where
好吧?
you get the essentials of what you're doing, right in there
你得到的必需品,你在做什么,对吧
in line, So, you're not having to go look at some other
,所以,你不必去看一些其他的
method somewhere like changeSign up here,
方法在某个地方像changeSign,
The other thing closures allow you to do, is to pass off to
另一个闭包允许你做的是,通过去
methods some piece of code to execute if something fails,
方法的代码执行如果失败,
or when something completes, Or do this and
当事情完成后,或者这样做
animate it, while you're doing it, for example, You're gonna
动画,当你这样做,例如,你会
see API like that, So, being able to pass these methods
看到这样的API,所以,能够通过这些方法
around, you're gonna see, Really makes for great, great
你会看到,真的是伟大的,伟大的
API, So, you're just seeing the simplest possible use of
API,所以,你只是看到最简单的使用
it here, We just using as the associated value, but imagine
在这里,我们只使用相关的值,但想象
it as function, parameters and things like that, It's,
这是函数,参数之类的东西,,
it's pretty incredible, Okay, so let's go see if that works,
很不可思议的,好吧,让我们去看看效果如何,
All right, 4 x 5 = 20, square root, cosine,
好吧,4 x 5 = 20,平方根,余弦,
change sign, pi, cosine, this all working beautifully,
改变符号,π,cos,这都工作得很出色,
And now, we can add as many new operations as we want,
现在,我们可以添加尽可能多的新操作,
with one line each, okay, So, you see how I built a struct
每一行,好的,所以,你看看我建了一个结构体
here that's extensible without having to do sub-classing, and
这是可扩展的,而不必做生成子类,和
all that stuff, I can just add thing, and I could even go
所有的东西,我可以添加的东西,我甚至可以去
further and make this public, If I make this operations
进一步公开这个,如果我把这个操作
table public, I also have to make operation public,
表,我也不得不公开操作,
then other people can get my calculator brain int and
然后别人就可以让我的大脑int和计算器
add operations to it, okay? So very,
添加操作,好吗?
very sensible, not requiring any subclassing whatsoever,
非常明智的,不需要任何子类化,
So, structs can often be just as good,
因此,结构常常可以一样好,
if not a little bit better design point for
如果没有一点更好的设计点
classes, All right, the last thing that I wanna do here,
类,好吧,我想做的最后一件事,
Let's go back to our simulator, Is talk about
让我们回到我们的模拟器,谈论
the layout of the UI, You see I have this layout right here,
界面的布局,你可以看到我有这里的布局,
Let's look what happens if I rotate this into landscape
让我们看看发生了什么如果我旋转这个格局
mode, So, I'm gonna go up here in the simulator, and
模式,所以,我要在模拟器上,和
go to Hardware, Rotate Left, Okay, my calculator is
去硬件、左旋转,好吧,我的计算器
now completely unusable, Okay, cuz there's no equals, so
现在完全无法使用,因为没有=,
I can't even do five times three equals, right? So
我甚至不能做五乘以三等于,对吧?
it's completely useless, I guess I can still do pi,
它是完全无用的,我想我仍然可以做π,
mm, but it's clear that's not what you want, right?
毫米,但很明显,不是你想要的,对吧?
When you rotate, you wanna use that space in that way, okay?
当你旋转时,你想用这个空间,好吗?
And I promised you we were gonna build a UI that would
我答应你我们会建立一个UI
work in all those things, and, in fact,
在所有这些东西,事实上,
we're gonna do that right now, Let's go back to our UI,
我们要做的,现在,让我们回到我们的UI,
and doing this is not gonna require any change to
而这样做是不需要任何改变
our controller or our model, Okay,
我们的控制器或我们的模型,
this is purely something we're gonna do in the view, and
这纯粹是我们要做的在视图中,和
we're gonna do it with this business up down here, Okay,
我们要做这个业务了,好吧,
this multiple phones that we'll be able to click here,
这多个手机,我们就可以点击这里,
and see how things look in all these different
看看看看所有这些不同的东西
orientations right here, And out basic strategy
方向,基本策略
is we're gonna stack all these buttons into rows, and then
所有这些按钮是我们将堆栈到行,然后呢
we're gonna stack all those rows on top of each other,
我们要彼此堆栈之上的那些行,
And then we're gonna stack that with the display, to make
然后我们会显示堆栈,
this kind of block that has our UI, Then we're gonna tie
这种块,我们的UI,那么我们将领带
the edges of that block, to the edges of the device, So,
块的边缘,边缘的设备,因此,
that as the device changes, that block of stuff, gets
随着设备的变化,块的东西,
stretched out, or whatever, And the stuff inside,
伸出,之类的,里面的东西,
is gonna automatically now how to resize the buttons and
现在会自动按钮和如何调整
stuff to lay out, Okay, so that's all that we need to do
的东西,好了,这就是我们需要做的一切
to make that happen, To have nice rows and columns here,
做到这一点,这里有漂亮的行和列,
I'm gonna add one more button which you need for
我要你需要的加多一颗钮扣
your homework anyway, Which is a dot button, One of your
你的家庭作业,这是一个点按钮,你的一个
homework assignment items, is to make floating point input
作业项目,是使浮点输入
possible, This is already a floating point calculator,
可能,这已经是一个浮点计算器,
I can say 4, 45, Well, I can't type here, sorry,
我可以说4,45,我这里打不了,对不起,
But I can type 45 and hit square root, And
但我可以类型45和平方根,和
it would give me a floating point number, right?
它会给我一个浮点数,对吧?
But you can't enter any floating point numbers,
但是你不能输入任何浮点数,
'cuz there's no dot, right? So,
因为没有点,对吗?
that's part of your assignment,
这是你的任务的一部分,
So, I'll put that in there for you, Okay, so now,
所以,我帮你把它放在那里,好了,现在,
I'm gonna take this row, And I'm gonna put it into a stack,
我要把这一行,我要把它放到一个堆栈,
It's gonna be a horizontal stack on its side, And you do
它会是一个水平叠加,和你
that up here with editor, Embed in Stack View, okay?
上面的编辑器中,嵌入在堆栈视图中,好吗?
So, when I do that, see, it stacks them up horizontally,
所以,当我这样做,看,它栈水平,
And I can inspect that stack, it's selected right here,
我可以检查堆栈,选择在这里,
And you can see Stack View right there, it's horizontal,
你可以看到堆栈视图,它是水平的,
I'm gonna put some spacing in there, 10 points of spacing,
我要把一些间隔,间隔10分,
I'm also gonna make sure, that they're equally spaced,
我也要确保,他们是等距的,
So, I want each of the squares in there to be the same width,
所以,我希望每个广场上有相同的宽度,
All right, so same thing here, Let's go this one,
一样好,所以在这里,我们去这一个,
Now, there's actually another way besides going up here,
现在,这里是另一种方式除了上升,
editor, embed in, There's a button right here for it, So
编辑器中,嵌入,这里有个按钮,
common, there's a button right there, Embed in Stack,
常见的,有一个按钮,嵌入在堆栈,
so boom, I'll do that, Again, I'll put a space in here,
因此繁荣,我会这样做,再一次,我把一个空间在这里,
Notice that the cosine button is wider than the 1, 2, 3,
注意,cos按钮是更广泛的比1,2,3,
So, I'm gonna say fill equally and
所以,我同样会说填补
make them all the same width again,
让他们都是一样的宽度,
Oops, sorry, again, so we'll do 10 and
哦,不好意思,再一次,所以我们要做10
fill equally, Same thing here,
同样,这里也一样,
stack, Fill equally, 10 and we'll stack this one,
堆栈,填补同样,10和我们将堆栈,
Oops, dammit, Okay, now I'm gonna take these horizontal
哦,该死的,好吧,现在我要把这些水平
stacks, These five horizontal and stack them vertically, So,
堆栈,这五个水平和垂直堆栈他们,所以,
I'm gonna embed, Notice that it's pretty smart,
我要嵌入,注意,它很聪明,
It noticed they were above each other so
注意到他们彼此所以上空
it would automatically put it in a vertical stack, But,
它就会自动把它在一个垂直堆栈,但是,
it pushed them all over to the left in the stack, and I
都把他们留在堆栈,和我
want them to spread out across the stack, So, I'm gonna have
想让他们分散在整个堆栈,所以,我要
the alignment here, instead of leading, be fill, and
这里的对齐,而不是领导,被填满,
that's gonna fill the whole width, And of course I want
会填满整个宽度,当然,我想要的
spacing here as well, so we'll do that, So look at this,
间距在这里,所以我们要做的,所以看这个,
I got this beautiful keyboard, keypad right here for
我得到这个美丽的键盘,键盘在这里
my calculator, Now, I'm gonna hook that up to this display,
计算器,现在,我要钩,这显示,
I'm just gonna select them both, and
我要选择它们,
say stack them, Okay, puts them into a stack, The left
堆栈他们说,好吧,将它们放置到一个堆栈,左边
line aligned it again, leading aligned it there so
行排列一遍,主要有所以保持一致
I'm gonna say fill, I don't want fill equally here though,
我会说,我不希望填补同样如此,
Cuz if I do fill equally here, it's gonna make this display
因为如果我做填补同样在这里,它会显示
the same height as the whole keypad, so
整个键盘,一样的高度
I don't want that, So I just want fill,
我不希望这样,所以我只是想要填补,
I want to fill this space, but I do want the spacing here so
我想填补这一空间,但我想这里的间距
we'll do 10 points again, So, now that my whole UI in a nice
我们会再次10分,所以,现在我的整个界面漂亮
whole rectangle here, And I'm just gonna tie the edges,
整个矩形,我要领带的边缘,
of this UI to the edges of the device basically, okay,
这个UI的边缘设备的基本上,好吧,
Now, I'm gonna start here, whoops, I'm gonna start, yeah
现在,我要开始在这里,哦,我要开始,是的
be careful a little about that too, If you click on something
小心一点,如果你点击
and drag it, see you might try to drag the inner one away,
并拖动它,看到你可能会试图把内心的一个,
A trick for not doing that, there's two tricks,
技巧不这样做,有两个技巧,
One, is you can do command shift I believe it is, yeah,
一个,你可以命令转变我相信,是的,
Command shift will let you pick which one you want,
命令将会让你选择哪一个你想要的,
under the mouse, Actually it's control shift,
下鼠标,实际上是控制转变,
Control shift under the mouse let's you pick it, But,
控制转变下鼠标你选吧,但是,
another easy way is to use drag select,
另一个简单的方法是使用拖动选择,
to select the one you want, and then pick it up,
选择一个你想要的,然后把它捡起来,
Okay, so I'm gonna use the blue lines, actually, to put
好的,所以我要用蓝线,实际上,把
this at the proper space on the left edge and top,
在适当的左边缘和顶部空间,
And now I'm gonna do the magic to hook it to an edge, And
现在我要做魔法钩边,和
I do that with the Ctrl key, just like we did dragging into
我使用Ctrl键,就像我们做拖
the code, But here, I'm gonna drag from this selected thing,
代码,但在这里,我要把这个选择的事情,
Make sure the whole thing is selected, And
确保选中整个事情
Ctrl+Drag up to the top, So we can tie it to the top,
Ctrl +拖到顶部,所以我们可以把它绑在上面,
And when you let go, it's gonna say,
当你放手时,它会说,
what relationship do you want between this big box and
你想要什么关系之间这个大盒子
the top? And, and really it's talking about the outer edge,
顶部?
And you can try and make them the same width, or
你可以试着让他们相同的宽度,或
the same height, which really doesn't make sense here,
相同的高度,真的没有意义,
Or you can pin this vertical spacing to the top
或者你可以销垂直间距
layout guide,
布局指导,
So I basically pinned it to the top, And same thing here,
所以我基本上固定上山顶,这里也一样,
I can go to the left and pin the leading space, And
我可以去左边和销的主要空间,和
I can go to the right and pin, pin the trailing space, And
我可以去正确的销,销后空间,
I can go to the bottom and sorry, yes, the bottom, and
我可以去底部,对不起,是的,底部,
pin the bottom space, the vertical space in the bottom,
销空间底部,底部的垂直空间,
Now we're just seeing pinning it to edges, but you can use
现在我们只是看到把它的边缘,但您可以使用
this mechanism to Ctrl+Drag between any two elements and
这种机制Ctrl +拖动任意两个元素之间
say, make these two the same width, line up the left edges,
说,让这两个相同的宽度,排队左边缘,
line up the tops,
排队,
You see what I'm saying? And
你看到我在说什么吗?
once you have that ability to have all your items have rules
一旦你有你所有的物品有规则的能力
of their relation to each other, now you can imagine how
他们的相互关系,现在你可以想象
you can rotate the whole thing and have it all look good,
你可以旋转整个事情看起来都很好,
because it's following rules about what to do,
因为它是规则后要做什么,
Now one thing about these two pins, okay, those I pinned to
现在关于这两个别针,好吧,这些我固定
where I wanted them, But these two pins are not what I want,
我希望他们,但这两个别针不是我想要的,
It's pinning it this far from the edge, So
把它远离边缘,所以
how do I fix that? You can actually double-click on that,
我怎么解决这个问题?
If you double-click on this I-beam,
如果你双击这个工字梁,
it says, yes, I'm pinning this 113 points from the edge, And
它说,是的,我把这个113分的优势,和
you can go up here and try to pick Standard Value,
你可以在这里,选择标准的价值,
But that's grayed out, so we're gonna use 0,
但这是灰色的,所以我们要使用0,
So you almost want either Standard Value, if available,
所以你几乎要标准的价值,如果可用,
or 0, So in this case,
或0,所以在这种情况下,
0 means 0 points from this layout guide edge, okay? And
0意味着0分此布局指导,好吗?
same thing with this one down here, I'm gonna double-click,
一样的是下面这个,我要双击,
By the way, we can also see these things, okay?
顺便说一下,我们还可以看到这些东西,好吗?
If we select this, we can go over to the size inspector,
如果我们选择这个,我们可以去检查大小,
You can see all these things down at the bottom here,
你可以看到所有这些东西在底部,
okay, all these connections to the edges, right?
好的,所有这些连接边缘,对吧?
See this one's 301, So I'm gonna double-click on this
看到这一个301年的,所以我要双击
I-beam, and here, standard value is available, So I'm
工字梁,在这里,标准价值可用,所以我
gonna pick the standard value, okay? And it puts it there,
会选择标准的价值?
Now so they tied it to the bottom and stretched this out,
现在他们与底部延伸出来,
Now it didn't quite stretch out the way we wanted here,
现在没有伸出我们希望这里的方式,
right? So some of these, rows in the inside,
对吧?
we didn't get the right attributes on,
我们没有得到正确的属性,
So let's go back and check them all, We got fill equally,
让我们回去检查,我们得到了填充同样,
horizontally, and all of them, yeah? We do, right?
水平,他们所有人,是吗?
And how about this? Here I'm gonna use the Ctrl+Click,
和这个怎么样?
We'll pick this stack view, See this one, okay,
我们选择这个堆栈视图,看到这个,好吧,
this is this inner one, wants to also be filled equally,
这是内心,想也是同样,
right? We want all these rows, not including this top guy,
对吧?
but all these inner interior rows to be the same,
但所有这些内在内部行是一样的,
So I'm gonna go fill equally here to fix that,
这里我要填补同样为了解决这个问题,
okay? So now I have this thing that can stretch out,
好吧?
because it's got these stacks that have rules about
因为它有这些规则的堆栈
how to fill, And then I've hooked them to the edges, so
如何填补,然后我上他们的边缘,所以呢
that now when I switch orientations, it adjusts,
现在当我切换方向调整,
even if I go to a smaller device, okay? Or
即使我去一个小装置,好吗?
a large device, Now one thing that's
大型设备,现在一件事
interesting about the very smallest device, an iPhone 4,
有趣的最小设备,iPhone 4,
is that in this orientation, it can't fit everything, You
是在这个方向,它不能适应一切,你呢
see that? The display is just, it can't fit it, So this is
看到了吗?
why it's great to be able to see this in Interface Builder,
为什么它是伟大的在Interface Builder中能够看到这个,
cuz we can go back here and pick a smaller font, for
因为我们可以回到这里,选择一个较小的字体,
example, We can even, you know, have our font be
例子中,我们甚至可以,你知道,我们的字体
variable, but there's no way to have the font automatically
变量,但没有办法自动的字体
squinched down, unfortunately, There's no autoshrink for
皱眉——下来,不幸的是,没有autoshrink
buttons like there is for labels, So sorry about that,
按钮像有标签,所以很抱歉,
But we would pick a smaller font that would work upon all
但是我们将选择一个较小的字体,所有工作
of our platforms maybe, okay? All right, so we have this,
也许,我们的平台?
And, of course, now if we run it in the simulator, we can
当然,如果我们在模拟器上运行它,我们可以
rotate it in the simulator as well and see it working there,
在模拟器上旋转它,看到它在那里工作,
And if we had a device, we could run it on our device and
如果我们有一个设备,我们可以对我们的设备和运行它
do it there, So here we go, Here's our iPhone 7,
这样做,所以让我们开始,这是我们的iPhone 7,
7 times 9 equals, It's still working,
7 * 9 =,它仍然是工作,
Square root, that's good, And when we rotate,
平方根,这很好,当我们旋转,
by the way, I'm gonna rotate using Command key,
顺便说一下,我将使用命令键,旋转
Okay, Command left and right arrows, you'll see it down in
好的,命令左右箭头,你就会看到它
the lower left corner here, but Command Rotate,
左下角,但是命令旋转,
See that? Okay, so you can see we had to do very little
看到了吗?
to make this thing adapt, And this is a fairly simple UI,
使适应,和这是一个相当简单的UI,
a lot of rectangles, More complicated UI,
大量的矩形,更复杂的用户界面,
we'd do a little bit more, And in about week five, four or
我们做一点,在星期5,四、
five, I'll go into detail about how we build these, even
5、我去详细说明如何构建这些,甚至
for complicated UIs how we build these rotatable things,
对于复杂的ui如何构建这些可循环的东西,
etc, Okay, so that's it, Your homework
等好了,就是这样,你的作业
is basically to reproduce what I did in these first two
基本上是复制这些前两个我在什么
lectures and then add a couple of things,
讲座,然后添加一些东西,
Add a little label up there, add some buttons, change some
添加一个小标签,添加一些按钮,改变一些
colors, that kind of business, pretty straightforward,
颜色,这样的生意,很简单的,
Make it work with floating point inputs and
使它与浮点输入和合作
that's due next Wednesday, I'm here if you have questions,
这是因为下个星期三,我在这里,如果你有问题,
and I'll see you then, >> For more,
到时候见,更多> >,
please visit us at stanford,edu,
请访问我们在斯坦福,edu,